<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><root>
<stage>[Disney's Mulan</stage>
<stage>Compiled by Barry Adams during theater showings in 1998</stage>
<sp><speaker>Last updated</speaker> August 18, 1998</sp>
<sp><speaker>Source</speaker> The Internet Movie Scripts Database (IMSDb): https://imsdb.com/scripts/Mulan.html]</sp>
<stage>Mulan is the property and copyright of the Walt Disney Company, Inc.  The</stage>
<stage>script on this page was compiled while watching Mulan in the theater during</stage>
<stage>the summer of 1998 when the film originally aired.]</stage>

<stage>[Chinese guard is seen walking on The Great Wall.  Shan-Yu's falcon swoops</stage>
<stage>down and hits the guard on the head knocking his helmet off.  The falcon lands</stage>
<stage>on top of a flag pole in front of a full moon and lets out a large cry.  One</stage>
<stage>grappling hook comes over The Great Wall.  The guard walks over to the edge</stage>
<stage>and sees many grappling hooks coming towards him]</stage>

<stage>Guard [yelling]:  We're under attack!  Light the signal!</stage>

<stage>[Guard runs to the tower and up the ladder as Hun Bald Man #1 and Hun Long</stage>
<stage>Hair Man appear trying to stop him.  Hun Bald Man #1 breaks the ladder with</stage>
<stage>his sword just as Guard reaches the top.  The guard picks up the torch to</stage>
<stage>light the fire and sees Shan-Yu jump over the edge of the tower and looks at</stage>
<stage>him across from the caldron.  The guard throws the torch into the caldron</stage>
<stage>lighting a large fire.  Shan-Yu watches as each tower lights their caldrons</stage>
<stage>one by one]</stage>

<stage>Guard [sternly]:  Now all of China knows you're here.</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [taking the flag and holding it over the fire]:  Perfect.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to the palace.  The large doors to the central chamber open as General Li</stage>
<stage>walks in flanked on his left and right by soldiers and approaches the Emperor. </stage>
<stage>He bows, then looks up]</stage>

<sp><speaker>General Li</speaker> Your Majesty, the Huns have crossed our Northern border.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Impossible! No one can get through The Great Wall.  [The Emperor</sp>
<stage>motions for Chi Fu's silence]</stage>

<sp><speaker>General Li</speaker> Shun-Yu is leading them.  We'll set up defenses around your</sp>
<stage>palace immediately.</stage>

<stage>Emperor [forcefully]:  No!  Send your troops to protect my people.  Chi Fu, </stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Yes, your highness.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> Deliver conscription notices throughout all the provinces.  Call up</sp>
<stage>reserves and as many new recruits as possible.</stage>

<sp><speaker>General Li</speaker> Forgive me your Majesty, but I believe my troops can stop him.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> I wont take any chances, General.  A single grain of rice can tip</sp>
<stage>the scale.  One man may be the difference between victory and defeat.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan using her chopsticks to single out a grain of rice on top of the</stage>
<stage>mound of rice]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Quiet and demure...graceful...polite...[picking up some rice with her</sp>
<stage>chopsticks and eating a mouthful] delicate...refined...poised... [She sets</stage>
<stage>down her chopsticks and writes down a final word on her right arm] punctual.</stage>
<stage>[A cock crows]  Aiya.  [Calling out]  Little brother. Little brother.  Lit-</stage>
<stage>ahhh, there you are.  Who's the smartest doggie in the world?  Come on smart</stage>
<stage>boy, can you help me with my chores today?</stage>

<stage>[Mulan ties a sack of grain around Little Brother's waist.  She ties a stick</stage>
<stage>onto Little brother so that end of it is in front of Little Brother's face. </stage>
<stage>She ties the bone on the end of the stick just out of reach.  Little Brother</stage>
<stage>begins to run after the bone which he cannot reach.  Mulan opens the door for</stage>
<stage>Little Brother and he runs into the door frame, then out the open door. </stage>
<stage>Little brother runs by the chickens and Khan - the family horse]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan's Father, Fa Zhou, kneeling and praying before the Fa family's</stage>
<stage>ancestors]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Honorable ancestors, please help Mulan impress the matchmaker today. </sp>


<stage>Little Brother [running into the temple and around Fa Zhou scattering grain</stage>
<stage>around the floor]: Bark, bark, bark, bark, bark.</stage>

<stage>[The chickens follow Little Brother into the temple and begin to feed on the</stage>
<stage>grain]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Please, PLEASE, help her.</sp>

<stage>[Mulan steps up to the temple seeing Little Brother on his hind legs trying to</stage>
<stage>get the bone.  Mulan bends the stick down so that Little brother can reach the</stage>
<stage>bone.  Little brother gnaws on the bone happily.  Mulan continues toward the</stage>
<stage>temple]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [calling out]: Father I brought your--whoop!  [Fa Zhou bumps into Mulan. </stage>
<stage>The cup falls to the ground and Fa Zhou catches the teapot with the handle of</stage>
<stage>his cane]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Mulan--</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> I brought a spare. [Mulan pulls out a cup from underneath the back of</sp>
<stage>her dress and begins to pour the tea]  </stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Mulan--</sp>

<stage>Mulan [hurried]: Remember, the doctor said three cups of tea in the morning--</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Mulan--</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> And three at night. </sp>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Mulan, you should already be in town.  We're counting on you to up--</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> --uphold the family honor.  Don't worry father.  I wont let you down. </sp>
<stage>[Mulan covers over the writing on her arm with here sleeve]  Wish me luck. </stage>
<stage>[Mulan hurries down the stairs]</stage>

<stage>Fa Zhou [calling out]:  Hurry!  [to himself] I'm going to...pray some more.</stage>
<stage>[Fa Zhou turns and walks back into the temple]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to the town with Fa Li looking worried]</stage>

<stage>Bath Lady [poking out of her building]:  Fa Li, is your daughter here yet? </stage>
<stage>The matchmaker is not a patient woman.  [She goes back into the building]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Li</speaker> Of all days to be late.  I should have prayed to the ancestors for</sp>
<stage>luck.</stage>

<stage>Grandma Fa [walking in with a Cri-Kee in a cage]:  How lucky can they be,</stage>
<stage>they're dead.  Besides,  I've got all the luck we'll need.  [Speaking to</stage>
<stage>Cri-Kee]  This is your chance to prove yourself.  [Cri-Kee chirps approvingly. </stage>
<stage>Grandma Fa covers her eyes steps into a busy street]</stage>

<stage>Fa Li [excitedly]:  Grandma No!</stage>

<stage>[The traffic barely misses Grandma Fa as she crosses the busy street.  But two</stage>
<stage>horse and carriage collide causing a big accident.  She arrives at the other</stage>
<stage>side of the street, uncovers here eyes and looks at Cri-Kee]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Grandma Fa</speaker> Yep, this cricket's a lucky one. [Cri-Kee falls over out of</sp>
<stage>fright]</stage>

<stage>Fa Li [sighing in relief]:  Hai.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan arrives on Khan jumping over the recent accident in the street and</stage>
<stage>jumps off with hay stuck in her hair]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> I'm here.  [Seeing a stern look from her mother] What?  But Mama I had</sp>
<stage>to--</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Li</speaker> None of your 'xcuses.  Now let's get you cleaned up. [They walk</sp>
<stage>together into the preparation area]</stage>

<stage>[Song: Honor to us all]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Bath Lady</speaker> [all the while Bath Lady undresses Mulan and pushes her into the</sp>
<stage>Bath]</stage>
<stage>This is what you give me </stage>
<stage>to work with?</stage>
<stage>Well, honey, I've seen worse.</stage>
<stage>We're gonna turn </stage>
<stage>this sow's ear</stage>
<stage>Into a silk purse. [Bath Lady moves the silk partition aside showing Mulan in</stage>
<stage>the bath] </stage>

<stage>Mulan [spoken]:  It's freezing.</stage>

<stage>Fa Li [spoken]:  It would have been warm if you were here on time.  </stage>

<stage>Bath Lady [washing Mulan's hair]:</stage>
<stage>We'll have you</stage>
<stage>Washed and dried</stage>
<stage>Primped and polished </stage>
<stage>till you glow with pride</stage>
<stage>Trust my recipe for </stage>
<stage>instant bride</stage>
<stage>You'll bring honor to us all</stage>

<stage>Fa Li [grabbing a sponge and Mulan's right arm to start cleaning her.  She</stage>
<stage>notices the writing] [spoken]:  Mulan, what's this?</stage>

<stage>Mulan [Drawing her arm back and batting her eyelashes] [spoken]:  Ahh, notes,</stage>
<stage>in case I forget something?</stage>

<stage>Grandma Fa [spoken]:  Here, hold this [hands the cricket to Fa Li].  We'll</stage>
<stage>need more luck than I thought.  [Mulan looks on with an air of disappointment]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to the hair dressers]</stage>

<stage>Hair Dresser 1 [Brushing and combing Mulan's hair much to Mulan's chagrin]:</stage>
<stage>Wait and see</stage>
<stage>When we're through</stage>

<stage>Hair Dresser 2:</stage>
<stage>Boys will gladly go to </stage>
<stage>war for you</stage>

<stage>Hair Dresser 1:</stage>
<stage>With good fortune </stage>

<stage>Hair Dresser 2 [Finalizing the hairdo to look exactly like hers]:</stage>
<stage>And a great hairdo</stage>

<sp><speaker>Both</speaker> </sp>
<stage>You'll bring honor to us all</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Li and others</speaker> [Mulan following her Mother passes a xiangqi game and</sp>
<stage>pauses to make an impressive move.  Mulan has a smug look on her face when Fa</stage>
<stage>Li comes back and drags Mulan away]</stage>
<stage>A girl can bring her family</stage>
<stage>Great honor in one way</stage>
<stage>By striking a good match</stage>
<stage>And this could be the day</stage>

<stage>Dresser 1 [Dresser 1, Dresser 2, and Fa Li dress Mulan]:</stage>
<stage>Men want girls </stage>
<stage>with good taste</stage>

<stage>Dresser 2:</stage>
<stage>Calm</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Li</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Obedient</stage>

<stage>Dresser 1:</stage>
<stage>Who work fast-paced</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Li</speaker> </sp>
<stage>With good breeding</stage>

<stage>Dresser 2 [Pulling the dress tight around her waist]:</stage>
<stage>And a tiny waist </stage>

<stage>Mulan [expressing her waist being squeezed tight] [spoken]: huh.</stage>

<sp><speaker>All Three</speaker> </sp>
<stage>You'll bring honor to us all </stage>

<sp><speaker>Chorus</speaker> [Mulan follows Fa Li and sees boy stealing a doll from a girl.  Mulan</sp>
<stage>grabs the doll from the boy and returns it to its owner]</stage>
<stage>We all must serve </stage>
<stage>our Emperor</stage>
<stage>Who guards us from the Huns</stage>
<stage>A man by bearing arms</stage>
<stage>A girl by bearing sons </stage>

<stage>Make-up Lady/Fa Li: [Putting on Mulan's face, powder, lipstick and eye liner]</stage>
<stage>[in a 3 person round]</stage>
<stage> When we're through </stage>
<stage>you can't fail</stage>
<stage>Like a lotus blossom </stage>
<stage>soft and pale</stage>
<stage>How could any fellow </stage>
<stage>say "No sale"</stage>
<stage>You'll bring honor to us all</stage>
<stage>[Make-Up Lady holds a mirror so Mulan can see her reflection.  Not looking</stage>
<stage>pleased, Mulan takes her single, short bang and brings it down in front of her</stage>
<stage>forehead and smiles]</stage>

<stage>Fa Li [spoken. Fa Li places a hair comb in Mulan's hair]:  There, you're</stage>
<stage>ready.</stage>

<stage>Grandma Fa [spoken]:  Not yet! An apple for serenity [putting an apple in</stage>
<stage>Mulan's mouth]...A pendant for balance [places a yin-yang pendant under her</stage>
<stage>sash] [sings]</stage>

<stage>Beads of jade for beauty [putting beads around Mulan's neck]</stage>
<stage>You must proudly show it [Grandma Fa raises her chin high with her hand]</stage>
<stage>Now add a cricket just for luck [putting the cage with Cri-Kee under Mulan's</stage>
<stage>sash in the back.  Cri-Kee doesn't look pleased]</stage>
<stage>And even you can't blow it</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> [Walking to catch up with the other maidens]</sp>
<stage>Ancestors</stage>
<stage>Hear my plea</stage>
<stage>Help me not to make a fool of me</stage>
<stage>And to not uproot my fam'ly tree</stage>
<stage>Keep my father standing tall</stage>

<sp><speaker>Maidens and Mulan</speaker> [Mulan taking the parasol from Fal Li and running to fall</sp>
<stage>in line with the other 4 maidens]</stage>
<stage>Scarier than the undertaker</stage>
<stage>We are meeting our </stage>
<stage>matchmaker</stage>

<sp><speaker>All Townspeople</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Destiny</stage>
<stage>Guard our girls</stage>
<stage>And our future </stage>
<stage>as it fast unfurls</stage>
<stage>Please look kindly on </stage>
<stage>these cultured pearls</stage>
<stage>Each a perfect porcelain doll</stage>

<stage>Maiden #1:  Please bring honor to us</stage>
<stage>Maiden #2:  Please bring honor to us</stage>
<stage>Maiden #3:  Please bring honor to us</stage>
<stage>Maiden #4:  Please bring honor to us</stage>
<sp><speaker>Mulan and Maidens</speaker> Please bring honor to us all! </sp>

<stage>[All Girls and Mulan arrive before the Matchmaker crouched down behind their</stage>
<stage>parasols.  End of song]</stage>

<stage>Matchmaker [looking at her clipboard]:  Fa Mulan</stage>

<stage>Mulan [Jumping up and raising her hand]:  Present.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Matchmaker</speaker> Speaking without permission.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Oops. </sp>

<stage>Grandma Fa [to Fa Li]:  Who spit in her bean curd?</stage>

<stage>[Mulan walks into the Matchmaker's building with the Matchmaker following</stage>
<stage>behind and closing the door]</stage>

<stage>Matchmaker [looking over Mulan]: Huh, Hmm, too skinny.  [Cri-Kee escapes from</stage>
<stage>his cage.  Mulan struggles to catch him] Hmph, not good for bearing sons. </stage>
<stage>[Mulan puts Cri-Kee in her mouth when Matchmaker turns around to face her]</stage>
<stage>Recite the final admonition.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [nodding and smiling]:  Mmm-Hmm.  [Takes out fan and covers her mouth as</stage>
<stage>she spits out Cri-Kee] Ptu</stage>

<sp><speaker>Matchmaker</speaker> Well...</sp>

<stage>Mulan [with dignity]: Fulfill your duties calmly and re...f--[looking at her</stage>
<stage>arm with smeared writing] spectfully.  Reflect before you snack [surprised,</stage>
<stage>Mulan looks at her arm again] act.  [now rapidly] This shall bring you honor</stage>
<stage>and glory.  [Fanning herself rapidly and sighing in relief] Huh.</stage>

<stage>Matchmaker [snatches the fan and looks at it on both sides looking for notes</stage>
<stage>not finding any.  Mulan smiles big when Matchmaker looks at her.  Matchmaker</stage>
<stage>grabs Mulan's right arm pulling her along while smearing the writing and</stage>
<stage>leaving some ink on her hand]  Hmmm, this way.  Now, pour the tea  [Pushing a</stage>
<stage>teapot towards Mulan].  To please your future in-laws you must demonstrate a</stage>
<stage>sense of dignity [Matchmaker smears ink around her mouth.  Mulan staring at</stage>
<stage>Matchmaker pours some tea onto the table then notices her mistake and pours</stage>
<stage>the tea into the cup] and refinement.  You must also be poised.  [Mulan</stage>
<stage>notices Cri-kee in the tea-cup as Matchmaker takes the cup]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [quiet and timid]:  Um, pardon me.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Matchmaker</speaker> And silent! [Matchmaker sniffs the tea]</sp>

<stage>Mulan [reaching and grabbing the teacup]:  Could I just take that back...one</stage>
<stage>moment.</stage>

<stage>[They struggle for the teacup and it turns over on Matchmaker and Cri-kee</stage>
<stage>jumps down matchmaker's dress]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Matchmaker</speaker> Why you clumsy--[Matchmaker feels Cri-Kee in her dress and dances</sp>
<stage>around]  Wooo, woooo, wooooooo, [Matchmaker knocks over her pot of coals, and</stage>
<stage>sits down on the coals.  Matchmaker jumps around screaming]  Ahhhhhhhhhhh </stage>
<stage>[Mulan grabs her fan and briskly fans the charred area on Matchmaker's behind</stage>
<stage>causing it to flame up.  Mulan looks surprised about her mistake]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to outside Matchmakers building showing Grandma Fa with much noise coming</stage>
<stage>from Matchmaker's building]</stage>

<stage>Grandma Fa [to Fa Li]:  I think it's going well, don't you?</stage>

<stage>Matchmaker [running out of the building screaming]:  Put it out! Put it out! </stage>
<stage>Put it out! [Mulan takes the teapot, throws the tea on Matchmaker and puts out</stage>
<stage>the fire.  She bows, hands the teapot back to Matchmaker and covers her face</stage>
<stage>as she walks toward Fa Li and Grandma Fa] [with anger]  You are a disgrace! </stage>
<stage>[Matchmaker throws the teapot down smashing it to pieces]  You may look like a</stage>
<stage>bride, but you will never bring your family honor!</stage>

<stage>[The townsfolk who have gathered whisper and walk away]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan walking through the gate with her home leading khan.  She looks</stage>
<stage>sorrowful.  Fa Zhou sees his daughter and smiles.  Mulan sees her father's</stage>
<stage>smile.  She covers her face with Khan's head and leads him to the water</stage>
<stage>trough]</stage>

<stage>[Song: Reflection]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Look at me [looking at her reflection in the water trough]</stage>
<stage>I will never pass for </stage>
<stage>a perfect bride [taking off her earrings and beads of jade]</stage>
<stage>Or a perfect daughter [Mulan watches Fa Li relating what happened at the</stage>
<stage>Matchmaker's to Fa Zhou]</stage>
<stage>Can it be</stage>
<stage>I'm not meant to play </stage>
<stage>this part?  [Mulan releases Cri-Kee back to the wild]</stage>
<stage>Now I see</stage>
<stage>That if I were to truly</stage>
<stage>To be myself [Mulan hops along the bridge railing]</stage>
<stage>I would break my </stage>
<stage>family's heart</stage>

<stage>Who is that girl I see  [Mulan looks into the pond and sees her own</stage>
<stage>reflection]</stage>
<stage>Staring straight</stage>
<stage>Back at me? [Mulan puts her hand on the Great Stone Dragon and looks toward</stage>
<stage>the temple]</stage>
<stage>Why is my reflection someone </stage>
<stage>I don't know? [Cri-Kee rowing across the pond on a lily pad]</stage>
<stage>Somehow I cannot hide [Mulan walking into the family temple]</stage>
<stage>Who I am [Cri-Kee watches Mulan in the temple seeing multiple reflections of</stage>
<stage>herself in the ancestors' stones]</stage>
<stage>Though I've tried  [Mulan bows to the ancestors]</stage>
<stage>When will my reflection show</stage>
<stage>Who I am inside?  [Mulan finishes wiping off her make-up seeing her reflection</stage>
<stage>in the stones]</stage>
<stage>When will my reflection show</stage>
<stage>Who I am inside? [Mulan gets up and heads out the temple]</stage>

<stage>[End of song.  Mulan sits on a bench under the blossom tree.  Fa Zhou</stage>
<stage>approaches her, clearing his throat.  Mulan sees him approaching and turns her</stage>
<stage>head away.  Fa Zhou sits down beside Mulan]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> My, my, what beautiful blossoms we have this year [looking up into</sp>
<stage>the blossom tree].  But look, this one's late.  But, I'll bet that when it</stage>
<stage>blooms, it will be the most beautiful of all.  [Mulan and Fa Zhou share</stage>
<stage>smiles.  Drums start pounding announcing the arrival of Chi Fu and two guards</stage>
<stage>on horseback]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> What is it?</sp>

<stage>[Fa Zhou gets up and walks to the entrance of their house with Mulan</stage>
<stage>following]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Li</speaker> Mulan, stay inside.</sp>

<stage>[Grandma Fa clears her throat catching Mulan's attention and motions inside. </stage>
<stage>Mulan spies the railing near the wall and climbs up to watch over the roof]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Citizens  I bring you a proclamation from the Imperial City:  the</sp>
<stage>Huns have invaded China! </stage>

<stage>Townspeople [expressing surprise]:  No!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> By order of the Emperor, one man from every family must serve in the</sp>
<stage>Imperial Army.  The Xiao family [a family member steps up, bows to the guard</stage>
<stage>and takes the conscription notice from the guard].  The Yi family.</stage>

<stage>Yi's Son [holding his old father back]:  I will serve the Emperor in my</stage>
<stage>father's place.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> The Fa Family.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> No.</sp>

<stage>[Fa Zhou gives his cane to Fa Li and walks toward Chi Fu.  Fa Zhou bows before</stage>
<stage>the horsemen]</stage>

<stage>Fa Zhou [standing proud]:  I am ready to serve the Emperor.  [Fa Zhou reaches</stage>
<stage>for the conscription notice]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [running outside to keep her father from taking the conscription</stage>
<stage>notice]:  Father, you can't go.</stage>

<stage>Fa Zhou [turning to see his daughter]:  Mulan!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Please sir, my father has already fought bravely--</sp>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Silence!  You would do well to teach your daughter to hold her tongue</sp>
<stage>in a man's presence.</stage>

<stage>Fa Zhou [looking away from Mulan]:  Mulan, you dishonor me.</stage>

<stage>[Grandma Fa guides Mulan back away]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [handing Fa Zhou the conscription notice]:  Report tomorrow at the Wu</stage>
<stage>Shu camp.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Yes, sir. [Fa Zhou walks back into the homestead refusing to take</sp>
<stage>his cane from Fa Li]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [fading out as we follow Fa Zhou]:  The Chu family.  The Wen family. </stage>
<stage>The Chang family.  The...</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Fa Zhou in his armory at night.  Fa Zhou takes out his sword and</stage>
<stage>practices his stances.  Whan he balances on his right leg, his leg injury acts</stage>
<stage>up and he falls.  Unbeknownst to her father, Mulan watches in horror.  She</stage>
<stage>breathes heavily]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to dinner.  The Fa Zhou, Grandma Fa, Fa Li, and Mulan eat in silence. </stage>
<stage>Thunder can be heard and lightning can be seen through the opaque window. </stage>
<stage>Mulan pours the tea for her family.  She slams her teacup down on the table</stage>
<stage>and stands up]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> You shouldn't have to go.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Fa Li</speaker> Mulan!</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> There are plenty of young men to fight for China.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> It is an honor to protect my country and my family.</sp>

<stage>Mulan [angrily]:  So you'll die for honor!</stage>

<stage>Fa Zhou [standing up and angered]:  I will DIE doing what's right.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [starts to speak but is cut off]: But if you--</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> I know my place, it is time you learned yours.</sp>

<stage>[Mulan looking like she's about to cry, turn away from Fa Zhou and runs</stage>
<stage>outside into the rain storm and cries]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan sitting at the base of the Great Stone Dragon in the rain. </stage>
<stage>Mulan looks down to see her reflection in the puddle caused by the rain. She</stage>
<stage>watches her parents in the bedroom.  Fa Li turns away from Fa Zhou and walks</stage>
<stage>out of site.  Fa Zhou blows out the light.  Mulan gets up and walks to the Fa</stage>
<stage>Family Temple.  Mulan's image reflects off the stone tablets as she lights</stage>
<stage>incense and places it in the hanging encense holder.  She bows and prays to</stage>
<stage>her ancestors. Getting up, Mulan hurries down the steps.  Cri-Kee sees her and</stage>
<stage>hops down from above and follows her.  Mulan goes to her parent's bedroom and</stage>
<stage>takes the conscription notice replacing it with the hair comb her mother gave</stage>
<stage>to her.  She pauses to give her parents a loving, sorrowful look and hurries</stage>
<stage>out.  Cut to Mulan in the armory.  She opens the cabinet with the armor. </stage>
<stage>Using her father's sword, she cuts her hair short and ties it up above her</stage>
<stage>head.  She finishes putting on the armor and ties it in the front.  She takes</stage>
<stage>the sword and places it in the scabbard to her left.  Cut to Mulan in the</stage>
<stage>stable doorway.  Khan rears back in fright at the sight of Mulan.  Mulan goes</stage>
<stage>forward and comforts Khan letting him know her identity.  Mulan walks Khan out</stage>
<stage>of the stable, Cri-Kee watches from the ground as she passes by.  Mulan takes</stage>
<stage>one sorrowful glance back at her parents bedroom and rides Khan through the</stage>
<stage>gate and off to camp.]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to the face of a statue in the Fa Family Temple.  The eyes glow.  Cut to</stage>
<stage>Grandma Fa.  She wakes up with a start rising in bed.  Cut to Grandma Fa</stage>
<stage>walking into Fa Li and Fa Zhou's bedroom, both are in bed]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Grandma Fa</speaker> Mulan is gone.</sp>

<stage>Fa Zhou [waking up]:  What?  It can't be.  [Fa Zhou looks at his night stand</stage>
<stage>and notices the hair comb in place of his conscription notice.  He checks the</stage>
<stage>cabinet and sees his armor is gone.  He hurries outside] [calling out]  Mulan! </stage>
<stage>[He stumbles while walking because of his leg injury] No.</stage>

<stage>Fa Li [kneeling down beside the fallen Fa Zhou]:  You must go after her.  She</stage>
<stage>could be killed!</stage>

<stage>Fa Zhou [sadly]:  If I reveal her, she will be. [Fa Zhou embraces Fa Li]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Grandma Fa</speaker> Ancestors, hear our prayer: Watch over Mulan.</sp>

<stage>[Cut to the Fa Family Temple.  A wind blows out the incense at the base of the</stage>
<stage>center stone.  The center stone begins to glow as First Ancestor comes to</stage>
<stage>life]</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [motioning to a bronze dragon]:  Mushu, awaken!</stage>

<stage>[Mushu comes to life and falls to the ground flat on his back all being</stage>
<stage>obscured by smoke]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [rising from the smoke arms stretched out]:  I live!  So tell me what</stage>
<stage>mortal needs my protection Great Ancestor.  You just say the word and I'm</stage>
<stage>there.</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [agitated]:  Mushu!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Hey, let me say something. Anybody who is foolish enough to threaten</sp>
<stage>our family, vengeance will be MINE.  Hrrrrr.</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [sternly to silence Mushu]:  Mushu!  These are the family</stage>
<stage>guardians [motioning towards the stone statues on pedestals near the ceiling]. </stage>
<stage>They...</stage>

<stage>Mushu [dejectedly]:  Protect the family.</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [pointing to the empty pedestal]:  And you, oh demoted one.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> I...ring the gong.</sp>

<sp><speaker>First Ancestor</speaker> That's right, now, wake up the ancestors.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> One family reunion coming right up.  [ringing the gong] Okay people,</sp>
<stage>people look alive, lets go! C'mon get up.  Let's move it, rise and shine. </stage>
<stage>You're way past the beauty sleep thing now trust me!</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 1:  I knew it, I knew it. That Mulan was a trouble maker from the</stage>
<stage>start.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 3:  Don't look at me, she gets it from your side of the family.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 2:  She's just trying to help her father.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 4 [appearing out of thin air]:  But, if she is discovered, Fa Zhou</stage>
<stage>will be forever shamed.  Dishonor will come to the family.  Traditional values</stage>
<stage>will disintegrate.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 5:  Not to mention they'll lose the farm.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 1:  My children never caused such trouble.  They all became</stage>
<stage>acupuncturists.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 3:  Well, We can't all be acupuncturists.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 6:  No, your great granddaughter had to be cross-dresser!</stage>

<stage>[All ancestors argue at once, except First Ancestor]</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 7:  Let a guardian bring her back.  </stage>

<stage>Ancestor 8 [grabbing Mushu and bringing him next to a guardian]: Yeah, awaken</stage>
<stage>the most cunning.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 4 [taking Mushu and holding him next to the stone rabbit guardian]: </stage>
<stage>No, the swiftest.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 9 [grabbing Mushu and holding him next to the stone monkey guardian]: </stage>
<stage>No, send the wisest.</stage>

<sp><speaker>First Ancestor</speaker> Silence!  We must send the most powerful of all [Motioning to</sp>
<stage>the Great Stone Dragon as it is seen through the window]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [climbs up the empty guardian post laughing]:  Ho, ho, heh, heh. Okay,</stage>
<stage>okay, I get the drift, I'll go. [All Ancestors give a quick look of surprise</stage>
<stage>and laugh uncontrollably]  You all don't think I can do it.  Watch this here. </stage>
<stage>[Mushu produces a small flame from his mouth]  Ah, ha, Jump back, I'm pretty</stage>
<stage>hot huh.  Don't make me have to singe nobody to prove no point.</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [grabbing Mushu and pulling away from the post]:  You had your</stage>
<stage>chance to protect the Fa family.</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 6:  Your mis-guidance led Fa Deng to disaster.</stage>

<stage>Fa Deng [with his decapitated head on his lap]:  Yeah, thanks a lot.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> And your point is?</sp>

<sp><speaker>First Ancestor</speaker> The point is we will be sending a real dragon to retrieve</sp>
<stage>Mulan.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> What?  But I'm a real dragon.</sp>

<stage>First Ancestor [grabbing Mushu and pulling him away from the guardian post as</stage>
<stage>Mushu fights to hold on]:  You are not worthy of this spot.  Now, awaken the</stage>
<stage>Great Stone Dragon.  [First Ancestor throws Mushu out of the temple]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [looking back into the temple]:  So you'll get back to me on the job</stage>
<stage>thing.</stage>

<stage>[An ancestor throws Mushu's gong and hits Mushu in the face]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [walking with a slouch and banging the gong on the ground]:  Just one</stage>
<stage>chance is that too much to ask?  I mean, it's not like it'll kill ya.</stage>

<stage>Mushu [rings the gong and looks at the Great Stone Dragon]:  Yo rocky, wake</stage>
<stage>up!  You gotta go fetch Mulan.  [pauses as nothing happens.  Mushu walks over</stage>
<stage>to the side of the statue] C'mon boy, go get her, go on, [throws the gong</stage>
<stage>stick off the screen and whistles] Come on.  [Angrily while climbing up the</stage>
<stage>Great Stone Dragon] Grrr, Grrrr.  [speaking in his ear and banging the ear</stage>
<stage>with the gong] Hello, helloooooo. [curtly] Hello [bangs the gong extra hard</stage>
<stage>against the ear causing it to break off].  Uh oh.  [The Great Stone Dragon</stage>
<stage>crumbles to the ground, head intact minus the ear].  [knocks on the dragon's</stage>
<stage>head] Uh, Stoney, Stooooneeey.  Oh man, they're gonna kill me!</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [calling out through the temple window]:  Great Stone Dragon,</stage>
<stage>have you awaken? </stage>

<stage>Mushu [holding the head of the Great Stone Dragon up to that First Ancestor</stage>
<stage>can only see it's head and Mushu's body]:  Uhhh, Yes, I just woke up.  And I</stage>
<stage>am the Great Stone Dragon, good morning [Mushu waves].  I will go forth and</stage>
<stage>fetch Mulan.  Did, did I mention that I was the Great Stone Dragon?</stage>

<sp><speaker>First Ancestor</speaker> Go, The fate of the Fa Family rests in your claws.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Don't even worry about it, I will not lose face.  [Mushu falls down</sp>
<stage>the hill under the weight of the Great Stone Dragon's head and lands on the</stage>
<stage>dragon's pedestal with the head falling on top of him]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [muffled]:  Ow, my elbow.  Aw, aw, I know I twisted something. </stage>
<stage>[Throwing the head off him]  That's just great.  Now what?  I'm doomed!   And</stage>
<stage>all 'cause miss man decides to take her little drag show on the road.</stage>

<stage>[Cri-Kee enters stage right]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Cri-Kee</speaker> Chirp, Chirp.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Go get her?   What's the matter with you?  After this great stone</sp>
<stage>Humpty Dumpty mess, I'd have to bring her home with a medal to get back in the</stage>
<stage>temple.  Wait a minute, that's it!  I make Mulan a war hero, then they'll be</stage>
<stage>begging me to come back to work.  That's the master plan.  Oh, you've gone and</stage>
<stage>done it now. [Mushu runs off stage right]</stage>

<stage>Cri-Kee [hopping along side of Mushu]:  Chirp.  Chirp Chirp Chirp.</stage>

<stage>Mushu [pushing Cri-Kee away]:  Hey, what makes you think you're coming?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Cri-Kee</speaker> Chirp, Chirp. </sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> You're lucky?  Ho, ho, heh.  Do I look like a sucker to you?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Cri-Kee</speaker> Chirp. Chirp.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Whach' you mean loser?  How 'bout I pop one of your antenna's off and</sp>
<stage>throw it across the yard.  Then who's a loser, me or you?</stage>

<stage>[Interlude]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Shan-Yu leading his army at a charge on horseback through a forest. </stage>
<stage>He stops and motions stage right.  Hun Archer, Hun Strong Guy, Hun Long-Hair</stage>
<stage>Guy dismount and walk into the forest.  They throw down two Imperial scouts</stage>
<stage>before the rest of the army]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Hun Long-Hair Guy</speaker> Imperial scouts. </sp>

<stage>[Shan Yu dismounts and walks towards the scouts]</stage>

<stage>Scout #1:  Shan-Yu.</stage>

<stage>[He crouches down in front of them]</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [adjusting Scout #1's collar]:  Nice work, gentlemen.  You found the</stage>
<stage>Hun army. [motioning to the soldiers on horseback.  The Hun army laughs]</stage>

<stage>Scout #2:  The Emperor will stop you.</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [grabs Scout #2 by the shirt collar and lifts him up to his face]: </stage>
<stage>Stop me?  He invited me.  By building his wall, he challenged my strength. </stage>
<stage>Well I'm here to play his game  [Shan-Yu throws Scout #2 to the ground and</stage>
<stage>points his sword at Scout #1 as he gets up and runs] [calling out to the</stage>
<stage>scouts] Go!  Tell your emperor to send his strongest armies.  [Quietly]  I'm</stage>
<stage>ready. </stage>

<stage>[The Imperial Scouts run off towards the palace]</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [scratching his chin]:  How many men does it take to deliver a</stage>
<stage>message.</stage>

<stage>Archer Guy [drawing back his bow]:  One.</stage>

<stage>[End Interlude]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan on a hill outside of the camp.  Khan is sitting watching]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Okay, okay, how 'bout this?  Ahem, [in her manly voice] excuse me,</sp>
<stage>where do I sign in?  Hah, I see you have a sword.  I have one too.  They're</stage>
<stage>very manly and tough [Mulan bites her lip as she mishandles pulling the sword</stage>
<stage>out of the scabbard and it falls to the ground.  Khan rolls on his back in</stage>
<stage>laughter.  Mulan throws her shoe and hits Khan in the head with it quieting</stage>
<stage>Khan].  I'm working on it.  Who am I fooling?  It's going to take a miracle to</stage>
<stage>get me into the army.</stage>

<stage>[Mushu appears as a giant shadow being cast on a rock with flames on either</stage>
<stage>side.  Mushu's real appearance remains out of sight]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [in a Southern Baptist Preacher's voice]:  Did I hear someone ask for a</stage>
<stage>miracle!?  Let me hear you say aye!</stage>

<stage>Mulan [Running and hiding behind a rock]:  Ahhhhhh.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> That's close enough.</sp>

<stage>Mulan [from behind a rock]:  Ghost.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Get ready Mulan your serpentine salvation is at hand.  For I have</sp>
<stage>been sent by your ancestors-- [notices Cri-Kee making a hand shadow of a</stage>
<stage>dragon on the rock and stamps him down with his foot] to guide you through</stage>
<stage>your masquerade.  [bending down to Cri-Kee]  C'mon, you're gonna stay you're</stage>
<stage>gonna work. [returning to Mulan] Heed my word, 'cause if the army finds out</stage>
<stage>that you are a girl, the penalty is death. [big flames shoot up from the</stage>
<stage>rocks]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Who are you?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Who am I?  Who am I?  I am the guardian of lost souls. [Mulan smiles</sp>
<stage>big in anticipation of seeing her guardian] I am the powerful, the</stage>
<stage>pleasurable, the indestructible [coming out from the rocks to show his real</stage>
<stage>size] Mushu! Oh hah, hah, pretty hot, huh? [Khan stomps on Mushu.  Mulan</stage>
<stage>pushes Khan back]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Ah, my ancestors sent a little lizard to help me?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Hey, dragon, dragon,  not lizard.  I don't do that tongue thing [flips</sp>
<stage>out his tongue to show Mulan what he means].</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> You're uh...</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Intimidating?  Awe inspiring?</sp>

<stage>Mulan [making a hand gesture to denote his smallness of size]: Tiny.</stage>

<stage>Mushu [with a look of disappointment]:  Of course.  I'm travel size for your</stage>
<stage>convenience.  If I was my real size, your cow here [patting Khan on the nose]</stage>
<stage>would die of fright.  [Khan tries to bite Mushu]  [pointing to the ground</stage>
<stage>speaking to Khan] Down Bessy.  My powers are beyond your mortal imagination. </stage>
<stage>For instance, [leaning in and looking at Mulan's chest] my eyes can see</stage>
<stage>straight through your armor.  [Mulan cover her bust with her left arm and</stage>
<stage>slaps Mushu with the right]  Ow.  [angrily] All right, that's it!  Dishonor! </stage>
<stage>Dishonor on your whole family.  [aside to Cri-Kee] Make a note of this</stage>
<stage>[Cri-Kee grabs a leaf and a pen and starts writing].  [Loudly with gusto]</stage>
<stage>Dishonor on you.  Dishonor on your cow.  Dis-</stage>

<stage>Mulan [pleadingly while covering Mushu's mouth]:  Stop!  I'm sorry, I'm sorry</stage>
<stage>[kneeling down in front of Mushu].  I'm just nervous.  I've never done this</stage>
<stage>before.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Then you're gonna have to trust me.  And don't you slap me no more, we</sp>
<stage>clear on that?  [Mulan nods emphatically].  All right.  Okey dokey, let's get</stage>
<stage>this show on the road.  Cri-Kee, get the bags [Mushu starts walking to the</stage>
<stage>camp].  [to Khan] Let's move it heifer.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan at the camp's entrance]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [hiding in Mulan's armor poking his head out from her back]:  Okay this</stage>
<stage>is it, time to show 'em your man walk.  Shoulders back,  chest high, feet</stage>
<stage>apart, head up [Mushu pulls Mulan's head back]  ...and strut 2, 3, break it</stage>
<stage>down, 2, 3 and work it, [Mulan walks into the camp drawing the attention the</stage>
<stage>men who see her.  Mulan walks into a tent and sees a man picking his nose and</stage>
<stage>another man picking out dirt from between his toes with chopsticks] Beautiful</stage>
<stage>isn't it?</stage>

<stage>Mulan [making a face of disgust and continuing to walk]:  They're disgusting.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> No, they're men.  And you're going to have to act just like them, so</sp>
<stage>pay attention.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan stops and watches Yao, Ling, Chien-Po and Tattoo Soldier]</stage>

<stage>Tattoo Soldier [showing the dragon tattoo on his chest and belly]:  Look, this</stage>
<stage>tattoo will protect me from harm.</stage>

<stage>[Yao thinks for a moment, then punches Tattoo Soldier in the stomach causing</stage>
<stage>Ling to laugh.  Mulan watches in utter amazement.  Yao kisses his hand]</stage>

<stage>Ling [laughing]:  I hope you can get your money back.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> I don't think I can do this.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> It's all attitude.  Be tough like this guy here [looking at Yao].</sp>

<stage>[Mulan looks at Yao as he hocks up a loogie and spits]</stage>

<stage>Yao [noticing Mulan watching him]:  What are you looking at?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Punch him, it's how men say 'hello.'</sp>

<stage>[Mulan looks at her fist, then punches Yao from behind on the shoulder.  The</stage>
<stage>force causes Yao to run into Chien-Po]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chien-Po</speaker> Oh Yao, you made a friend.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Good, Now slap him on the behind, they like that.</sp>

<stage>[Mulan slaps Yao on the behind]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Wu hoo hooooo.  [grabbing Mulan buy the collar]  I'm going to hit you so</sp>
<stage>hard it'll make your ancestors dizzy.</stage>

<stage>Chien-Po [Holding and picking up Yao]:  Yao, relax and chant with me. </stage>
<stage>Yaaaaaaa Moouuuu Ahhhhhh Doooou Fuuuu Daaaaa.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Ya Mi Ah To Fu Da.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Chien-Po</speaker> Feel better? </sp>

<stage>Yao [relaxed]:  Yeah. [Chien-Po places Yao back on the ground]  [to Mulan</stage>
<stage>while walking away] Aaaaa, you ain't worth my time chicken boy.</stage>

<stage>Mushu [loudly]:  Chicken boy!?  Say that to my face ya limp noodle!</stage>

<stage>[Yao grabs Mulan by the collar cocking back his arm to punch.  Mulan ducks as</stage>
<stage>Yao hits Ling standing behind her]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Oh, sorry Ling.  Hey!</sp>

<stage>[Yao grabs Mulan's foot as she starts to crawl away.  Ling kicks Yao on the butt causing him to land on Chien-Po's stomach. Ling Jump</stage>
<stage>attacks Mulan, but she ducks and he lands on Yao on top of Chien-Po]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Ling</speaker> You're dead.  [They fight on top of Chien-Po.  Mulan runs away.  Ling notices Mulan and then points toward her] Oh, there he goes.</sp>

<stage>[Mulan runs into a tent and stops.  Yao, Ling, and Chien-Po (in that order) run through the tent.  Yao stops short as he is about to run into a</stage>
<stage>soldier in a line for food.  He looks behind him with concerned eyes as Ling stops in time.  Chien-Po bumps into Ling causing the entire line</stage>
<stage>of soldiers to fall forward and knock over the pot of congee and the cook behind it.  The men look to the back of the line and spy Mulan who</stage>
<stage>has emerged from the tent.  They angrily start walking towards her.  Mulan has a look of horror on her face as if trouble is about to brew]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Hey guys.  </sp>

<stage>[Chi Fu watches and then walks into the tent.  General Li and Li Shang are in the tent.]</stage>

<stage>General Li [motioning with his pointer to a map of the region]:  The Huns have struck here, here and here.  I will take the main troops up to</stage>
<stage>the Tung Shao Pass and stop Shan-Yu before he destroys this village.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Excellent strategy, Sir.  I do love surprises, Ha ha, ha, ha.</sp>

<sp><speaker>General Li</speaker> You will stay here and train the new recruits.  When Chi Fu believes you're ready, you will join us...Captain. [General Li hands</sp>
<stage>a sword to Shang]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Captain?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Oh, this is an enormous responsibility, General.  Uh, perhaps a soldier with more experience--</sp>

<sp><speaker>General Li</speaker> Number one in his class, extensive knowledge of training techniques, [leaning back smugly stroking his chin] an impressive</sp>
<stage>military lineage.  I believe Li Shang will do an excellent job.</stage>

<stage>Shang [excitedly]:  Oh, I will.  I wont let you down.  This is, I mean, I...[somberly] yes sir.</stage>

<stage>General Li [gets up and starts walking out of the tent]:  Very good then.  We'll toast China's victory at the Imperial City.  [to Chi Fu] I'll</stage>
<stage>expect a full report in three weeks.</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [to Shang]:  And I wont leave anything out.  [exits through the tent]</stage>

<stage>Shang [while tying his sword to his uniform]:  Captain Li Shang, Hmmm, leader of China's finest troops.  No, the greatest troops of all time. </stage>
<stage>Heh, heh, heh, heh.  [Shang walks out of the tent to see the recruits fighting.  He stands stage left of Chi Fu and General Li.  Injured Recruit</stage>
<stage>sees the General and salutes him as he falls to the ground.  General Li steps over Injured Recruit and mounts his horse]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Most impressive.</sp>

<sp><speaker>General Li</speaker> Good luck Captain.  [The general and his mounted troops leave the camp]</sp>

<stage>Shang [quietly, to himself]:  Good luck, Father.  [Shang looks at his troops and sighs]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [smirking, with board and brush in hand]:  Day one.</stage>

<stage>Shang [shouting]:  Soldiers!</stage>

<stage>All Recruits [backing away revealing Mulan and pointing at her.  Mulan is crouching in the fetal position on the ground]:  He started it!</stage>

<stage>[Shang approaches Mulan and looks down over her.  Mulan looks up, sees Shang over top of her and gets up quickly dusting herself off]</stage>

<stage>Shang [to Mulan]:  I don't need anyone causing trouble in my camp!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Sorry, [in her man voice] Uhh, I mean, sorry you had to see that.  [with her fist she taps Shang on the shoulder]  You know how it is</sp>
<stage>when you get those, uh [pounding her chest] manly urges and you just have to kill something [slapping her hand], fix things, uh, cook</stage>
<stage>outdoors.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> What's your name?</sp>

<stage>Mulan [stumbling]:  Ahh, I, uhhh, I, uh--</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [stepping into Mulan's face]:  Your commanding officer just asked you a question.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Uhh, I've got a name.  Huh.  And it's a boys name too.</sp>

<stage>Mushu [from the back of Mulan]:  Ling, How 'bout Ling?</stage>

<stage>Mulan [to Mushu motioning with her head to Ling]:  His name's Ling.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> I didn't ask for his name.  I asked for yours.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Try, uh, ahh, Chu!</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Ah Chu.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Ah Chu?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Gesundheit.  He He, I kill myself.</sp>

<stage>Mulan [whispering over her shoulder]:  Mushu.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Mushu?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> No.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Then what is it!</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Ping! Ping was my best friend growing up!</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> It's Ping.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Ping.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Of course Ping DID steal my gir-[Mulan reaches back and grabs holds Mushu's mouth together]</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Yes, my name is Ping.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Let me see your conscription notice.  [Takes the notice from Mulan]  Fa Zhou, *the* Fa Zhou?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> I didn't know Fa Zhou had a son.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Um, he...doesn't talk about me much.  [Mulan tries to hawk up a loogie and spit but the saliva just runs from her mouth.  The</sp>
<stage>recruits laugh]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> I can see why, the boy's an absolute lunatic.</sp>

<stage>Shang [to the recruits]: Okay gentlemen, thanks to your new friend Ping, you'll spend tonight picking up every single grain of rice.  And</stage>
<stage>tomorrow, the real work begins.</stage>

<stage>[All recruits growl at Mulan]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [Popping out the front of Mulan's armor]:  You know, we have to work on your people skills.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan sleeping in her tent.  Mushu winds up Cri-Kee's wings.  Cri-Kee rings like an alarm clock]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> All right, rise and shine sleeping beauty.  [Mulan rises and blinks] C'mon [rapping on Mulan's head with each syllable] hup, hup,</sp>
<stage>hup. [Mulan groans, lies back down and pulls the covers over her head.  Mushu pulls the covers off Mulan entirely]  Get your clothes on. </stage>
<stage>Get ready.  Got breakfast for ya.  [Mushu jumps onto Mulan's knee with a bowl of porridge]  Look, you get porridge, and it's happy to see</stage>
<stage>you.  [Mushu shows her the bowl with two eggs and bacon looking like a smiley face.  Cri-Kee pops up out from the bowl of porridge] Hey,</stage>
<stage>get outta there, you gonna make people sick!  [Mushu uses chopsticks to push Cri-Kee out of the porridge]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Am I late?</sp>

<stage>Mushu [while feeding Mulan]:  No time to talk.  Now remember, it's your first day of training so listen to your teacher and no fighting.  Play</stage>
<stage>nice with the other kids, unless of course one of the other kids wanna fight, then you have to kick the other kid's butt.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [with her mouth full of food]:  But I don't wanna kick the other kid's butt.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Don't talk with your mouth full.  Now let's see your war face [Mulan looks at him with wide eyes and chipmunk cheeks full of food]. </sp>
<stage>I think my bunny slippers just ran for cover.  C'mon scare me, girl! </stage>

<stage>Mulan [swallows the food]:  Rrrrrrr!</stage>

<stage>Mushu [rolling back into the half eaten bowl of porridge]:  Oh, that's my tough looking warrior.  That's what I'm talking about.  Now get out</stage>
<stage>there and make me proud. [Mushu ties up Mulan's hair]</stage>

<stage>[Khan whinnies and pokes his head into the tent]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> What do you mean the troops just left?  </sp>

<stage>Mulan [acting surprised]:  They what!? [Mulan hurriedly puts on her clothes and jumps out of the tent going off to join the other recruits]  </stage>

<stage>Mushu [running out from the tent calling after Mulan]:  Wait, you forgot your sword.  My little baby off to destroy people [sniffle].</stage>

<stage>[Cut to the troops muddling around near Shang's tent]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [enters stage left]:  Order people, order!</stage>

<stage>Recruit #2:  I'd like a pan fried noodle.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chien-Po</speaker> Oh, oh, sweet and pungent shrimp [Ling and others begin to laugh]</sp>

<stage>Recruit #3:  Moo goo gai pan</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> That's not funny.</sp>

<stage>[Mulan comes running up to the group]</stage>

<stage>Ling [noticing Mulan's arrival]:  Looks like our new friend slept in this morning.  [Mulan stops between Ling and Yao] [to Ping] Hellooo Ping,</stage>
<stage>Are you hungry?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Yeah, 'cause I owe you a knuckle sandwich.  [grabs Mulan by the shirt collar drawing back his other arm.  Mulan hides her face with</sp>
<stage>her hands.  Ling looks away, closes his eyes, and puts his fingers in his ears so that he wont hear anything]</stage>

<stage>All Soldiers [in agreement with Yao]:  Yeah.</stage>

<stage>Shang [loudly]:  Soldiers!  [The soldiers line up quicky.  Shang takes off his shirt and grabs a bow and quiver of arrows.  Mulan is duly</stage>
<stage>impressed by Shang's physique] You will assemble swiftly and silently every morning. [Shang walks down the line of soldiers] Anyone who</stage>
<stage>acts otherwise will answer to me.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Ooooo, tough guy.</sp>

<stage>Shang [turning around with knocked arrow pointing towards Yao]:  Yao.  [All recruits take a step back leaving Yao one step forward.  Shang</stage>
<stage>Points arrow skyward and shoots it into the top of a high pole]  Thank you for volunteering.  Retrieve the arrow.</stage>

<stage>Yao [bows to Shang]:  I'll get that arrow pretty boy.  And I'll do it with my shirt on.  [Yao prepares to leap onto that pole]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> One moment, you seem to be missing something.  [Chi Fu brings out two large bronze disks.  Shang takes out one disk and holds it</sp>
<stage>high speaking to all the troops]  This represents discipline  [Shang hands the weight to Yao and the weight falls to the ground taking Yao's</stage>
<stage>arm with it]  and this represents strength [Shang hands the other weight to Yao making him fall to the ground.  The troops laugh while</stage>
<stage>Mulan looks concerned].  You need both to reach the arrow.</stage>

<stage>[Yao climbs up the pole then slips down under the weight.  Ling, Chien-Po, and Mulan each take their turn and fall down.  Mulan rubs her</stage>
<stage>behind as she walks away in front of Shang]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> We've got a long way to go.</sp>

<stage>[Song I'll Make a Man Out of You]</stage>

<stage>[Shang throws staffs to the soldiers.  Yao intercepts Mulan's staff and trips her with it]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Let's get down to business--</stage>
<stage>to defeat the Huns.</stage>

<stage>[Shang throws up two clay pots and breaks them apart with his staff.  The troops are highly impressed]</stage>

<stage>Recruits [putting their staffs out at arms length, spoken]:  Hua</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Did they send me daughters</stage>
<stage> when I asked for sons?  [Ling puts a cricket down Mulan's back causing her to flail erratically]</stage>
<stage>You're the saddest bunch</stage>
<stage> I ever met  [Most soldiers fall as Mulan moves uncontrollably]</stage>
<stage>But you can bet </stage>
<stage>before we're through  [Shang does a somersault in the air landing near Mulan.  He takes a pole in the stomach.  Shang stops Mulan and</stage>
<stage>takes her staff.  He grabs her by the collar]</stage>
<stage>Mister, I'll make a man</stage>
<stage> out of you </stage>

<stage>[Shang steps on a lever throwing up 3 targets which he hits with 3 arrows from one bow]</stage>
<stage>Tranquil as a forest</stage>
<stage>[The recruits try and fail.  Mulan gets ready to fire when Mushu sticks a target on her arrow before she shoots.  Mulan looks at Mushu's in</stage>
<stage>shock and pauses.  Shang looks disdainfully at Mulan as she cracks a huge smile]</stage>
<stage>But on fire within</stage>
<stage>[Shang balances a bucket of water on his head holding a staff.  The recruits fire stones at him which Shang deflect with the staff]</stage>
<stage>Once you find your center</stage>
<stage>You are sure to win</stage>
<stage>[Mulan wobbles with the bucket of water on her head.  As the recruits throw stones at her the bucket tips over onto her head]</stage>
<stage>You're a spineless, pale,</stage>
<stage>pathetic lot </stage>
<stage>And you haven't got a clue </stage>
<stage>[Shang throws his hand down into a river and retrieves a fish.  Mulan throws her hand down into the river and retrieve's Yao's foot.  Mushu</stage>
<stage>comes out of the water with a fish in hand to give to Mulan]</stage>
<stage>Somehow I'll make a man</stage>
<stage>out of you!</stage>

<stage>Chien-Po [running through a field of fire arrows]:</stage>
<stage>I'm never gonna catch </stage>
<stage>my breath</stage>

<stage>Yao [following Chien-Po, falls and gets hit in the butt with an arrow]:</stage>
<stage>Say good-bye to those </stage>
<stage>who knew me</stage>

<stage>Ling [Banging his head on a stone slab]:</stage>
<stage>Boy I was a fool in school </stage>
<stage>for cutting gym</stage>

<stage>[Shang practices martial arts with Mulan.  With a punch to the face he knocks her back into a tree]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [from the tree acts as a boxing coach]:</stage>
<stage>This guy's got 'em </stage>
<stage>scared to death</stage>

<stage>Mulan [Mushu pushes Mulan back out into the ring]:</stage>
<stage>Hope he doesn't see </stage>
<stage>right through me</stage>

<stage>Chien-Po [stops as he's hopping across poles protruding from water causing Shang and the recruits to pile into him]:</stage>
<stage>Now I really wish that I </stage>
<stage>knew how to swim!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang and Chorus</speaker> </sp>
<stage>[Cannon fire misses the target in the middle of an open field. Ling kicks the support structure out from Mulan's cannon and it begins to fall.</stage>
<stage>Mulan quickly grabs the cannon and it fires high and back towards the camp landing and exploding Chi Fu's tent]</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>We must be swift as </stage>
<stage>the coursing river</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the force </stage>
<stage>of a great typhoon</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the strength </stage>
<stage>of a raging fire</stage>
<stage>[Picture of Shang looking over the camp from the hill not looking pleased]</stage>
<stage>Mysterious as the </stage>
<stage>dark side of the moon </stage>

<stage>Shang [his troops laden with poles on their shoulders carrying bags of grain - one on each side.  They march up a mountain]:</stage>
<stage>Time is racing toward us </stage>
<stage>till the Huns arrive  </stage>
<stage>[Chi Fu points Shang's eyes back to a struggling Mulan who falls to the ground.  Cri-Kee and Mushu try to pick her up but hide when Shang</stage>
<stage>comes up to her.  Shang picks up her pole with grain, puts it on top of his and returns to the troops. Mulan looks rejected]</stage>
<stage>Heed my every order </stage>
<stage>and you might survive</stage>
<stage>[Shang hand the reigns of Khan to Mulan]</stage>
<stage>You're unsuited for </stage>
<stage>the rage of war</stage>
<stage>So pack up, go home, </stage>
<stage>you're through</stage>
<stage>How could I make a man</stage>
<stage>out of you?</stage>

<stage>Shang and Chorus [Mulan takes the weights and tries to climb the pole again]:</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>We must be swift as </stage>
<stage>the coursing river</stage>
<stage>[Mulan ties the weights together behind the pole and uses the cloth to help her shimmy up the pole]</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the force </stage>
<stage>of a great typhoon</stage>
<stage>[As the sun begins to rise the recruits come out of their tents to cheer on Mulan]</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the strength </stage>
<stage>of a raging fire</stage>
<stage>[As Shang comes out of his tent, the arrow he shot up onto the pole comes down to his feet.  He looks up and sees Mulan sitting on top of</stage>
<stage>the pole]</stage>
<stage>Mysterious as the </stage>
<stage>dark side of the moon</stage>

<stage>[order of events during the last repeat of the chorus:</stage>
<stage>Troops hit all targets with arrows correctly.</stage>
<stage>Mulan racing in front of Shang and the recruits with the pole and weights on her shoulders.</stage>
<stage>Mulan kicking Shang in the face with a round house.  Shang looking pleased.</stage>
<stage>Chien-Po doing acrobatics on the poles as the troops follow.</stage>
<stage>Staffs being thrown to troops, Yao hands Mulan hers. </stage>
<stage>Yao running through arrows.</stage>
<stage>Yao grabs Mulan's staff and hands it to her.</stage>
<stage>Troop staff practice #1.  (Hya)</stage>
<stage>Ling breaking the block</stage>
<stage>Troop staff Practice #2.  (Hya)</stage>
<stage>Mulan holding up fish.</stage>
<stage>Troop staff practice #3.</stage>
<stage>Cannon fire hitting the Hun Target.</stage>
<stage>Troop staff practice #4 - jumping in the air (Hya)]</stage>
<stage>(Be a man) </stage>
<stage>We must be swift as </stage>
<stage>the coursing river</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the force </stage>
<stage>of a great typhoon</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the strength </stage>
<stage>of a raging fire</stage>
<stage>Mysterious as the </stage>
<stage>dark side of the moon</stage>

<stage>[End Song]</stage>

<stage>[Interlude]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Shan Yu sitting on top of a tree.  He cuts off the very top with his sword.  His falcon swoops buy and drops a doll.  Shan-Yu takes</stage>
<stage>the doll, sniffs it, looks surprised, and drops down to the ground]</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [tossing the doll to Hun Strong Man]:  What do you see?</stage>

<stage>Hun Strong Man [feeling the doll]:  Black pine, from the high mountains.  [Long Hair Hun Man takes the doll from Hun Strong Man.  Bald</stage>
<stage>Hun Man #1 takes a hair as it passes by him]</stage>

<stage>Bald Hun Man #1:  White horse hair.  Imperial stallions.  </stage>

<stage>Long Hair Hun Man [sniffing the doll]:  Sulfur, from cannons.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shan-Yu</speaker> This doll came from a village in the Tung Shao Pass, where the Imperial Army's waiting for us.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Hun Archer</speaker> We can avoid them easily.</sp>

<stage>Shan-Yu [shaking his head]:  No, the quickest way to the Emperor is through that pass.  Besides, the little girl will be missing her doll.  We</stage>
<stage>should return it to her.</stage>

<stage>[End Interlude]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan by the lake with Mushu, Khan, and Cri-Kee]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Hey, oh, ah, no, this is not a good idea.  What if somebody sees you?</sp>

<stage>Mulan [from behind the reeds]:  Just because I look like a man doesn't mean I have to smell like one.  </stage>

<stage>Mushu [holding a towel covering his eyes with his ears]:  So a couple of guys don't rinse out their socks, picky, picky, picky.  Well myself I</stage>
<stage>kinda like that corn chip's smell.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [running by Mushu and jumps into the lake splashing water on Mushu]:  Ahhhhhhh.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Okay, all right, all right, that's enough.  Now, c'mon, get out before you get all pruny and stuff [holding out a towel towards Mulan</sp>
<stage>keeping his eyes covered].</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Mushu, if you're so worried, go stand watch.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Yeah, yeah, [walking in a womanly fashion speaking in woman's voice] stand watch Mushu while I blow our secret with my stupid</sp>
<stage>girly habits. [back to normal] Humph, hygiene.</stage>

<stage>Cri-Kee [alarmed, tugging on Mushu's whiskers]:  Chirp, Chirp.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Me first! Me first! Me First! [Yao, Ling and Chien-Po run by Mushu smacking him in the face with colored boxers]</sp>

<stage>Mushu [gasps]:  Ah.  We're doomed!  There a couple of things I know they're bound to notice!</stage>

<stage>[Yao and Ling jump into the water.  Chien-Po dips in his toe to check temperature then jumps in causing a large wave.  Yao and Ling ride</stage>
<stage>the wave towards Mulan.  Mulan sees them and hides her face behind a lily pad]</stage>

<stage>Yao [calling]:  Hey, Ping.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan peeks over the lily pad and spreads it on the water covering her chest]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [speaking nervously and unnaturally in a manly voice]:  Oh hi guys, I didn't know you were *here*. [Yao, Ling and Chien-Po share</stage>
<stage>"this boy is strange" looks] I was just washing, so now I'm clean and I'm gonna go.  Bye, bye.  [Mulan hides behind a rock keeping her front</stage>
<stage>facing the rock]</stage>

<stage>Ling [from behind Mulan]:  Come back here.  I know we were jerks to you before so lets start over.  [extending his hand to shake hands with</stage>
<stage>Mulan]  Hi, I'm Ling!</stage>

<stage>Mulan [covering her chest with her left arm, she turns and shakes his hand with an outstretched right arm, smiling]:  Heh, heh.  [Mulan turns</stage>
<stage>and wades away from Ling and runs into Chien-Po]</stage>

<stage>Chien-Po [taking a lily pad off his head]:  And I'm Chien-Po.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [waving slightly and smiling]:  Hello Chien-Po.</stage>

<stage>[Yao stands on top of a rock looking down at the others.  Mulan looks down into the water and hides her eyes with her free hand]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> And I am Yao, king of the rock.  And there's nothin' you girls can do about it.</sp>

<stage>Ling [taking a fighting stance]:  Oh, yeah?  Well, I think Ping [elbowing Mulan] and I could take you.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [wading away]:  I really don't want to take him anywhere.</stage>

<stage>Ling [following Mulan]:  Ping, we have to fight!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> No we don't. [unnaturally]  We could just close our eyes and swim around.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Ling</speaker> C'mon don't be such a g--Ouch!  Something bit me.</sp>

<stage>Mushu [popping out of the water between Mulan and Ling]:  What a nasty flavor.</stage>

<stage>Ling [with fear and gusto]:  Snake!  </stage>

<stage>Chien-Po [while all three of them climb up the rock and on each other]: Snake, snake.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan whistles for Khan and wades back to shore.  Khan comes close enough to shore and Mulan hides behind Khan as she wraps a towel</stage>
<stage>around her body]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Yao, Ling and Chien-Po calmed down sitting on the rock]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Ling</speaker> Some king of the rock!  [Yao pushes him off the rock]</sp>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan with towel wrapped around her]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Boy, that was close.</sp>

<stage>Mushu [brushing his teeth]:  No, that was vile!  You owe me big!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> I never want to see a naked man again.  [the rest of the troops run by naked and jump into the lake]</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Hey, don't look at me.  I ain't biting any more butts.</sp>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan outside Chi Fu's Tent having dressed fully.  Chi Fu and Shang are talking from inside]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [fading in]:  You think your troops are ready to fight?  Hah!  They would not last a minute against the Huns.  </stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> They completed their training.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Those *boys* are no more fit to be soldiers than you are to be Captain.  Once the general reads my report, your troops will never</sp>
<stage>see battle.</stage>

<stage>Mushu [from outside the tent]:  Oh no you don't.  I've worked to hard to get Mulan into this war. [to Cri-Kee] This guy's messing with my</stage>
<stage>plan.</stage>

<stage>Shang [grabbing onto the front of Chi Fu's clip board]:  We're not finished.</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [pulling the board away]:  Be careful, Captain.  The General may be your father, but I am the Emperor's council.  And, oh, by the</stage>
<stage>way, huh, I got that job on my own.  [opens the entrance to the tent for Shang] You're dismissed.</stage>

<stage>[Shang storms out of the tent and starts to walk by Mulan]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [in a manly voice]:  Hey, I'll hold him and you punch, heh, heh...  [Shang walks by without reacting] or not.  [calling out to Shang] </stage>
<stage>For what it's worth, I think you're a great captain.  [Shang pauses to glance back, then continues forward]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [looking at Mulan's fixed gaze on Shang]:  I saw that!</stage>

<stage>Mulan [innocently]:  What?</stage>

<stage>Mushu [teasing]:  You like him don't you?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> No, I--</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Yeah right, Yeah sure.  Look,  [pointing to Mulan's tent] go to your tent.  [Mulan walks away with a look of delight. Mushu talks to</sp>
<stage>Cri-Kee]  I think it's time we took this war into our own hands [rubbing hands together].</stage>

<stage>[Mushu and Cri-Kee wait outside Chi Fu's Tent.  Chi Fu emerges with carrying a scrub brush and wrapped in a towel and with big</stage>
<stage>showering slippers on his feet.  He whistles as he walks off.  Mushu and Cri-Kee enter his tent.  Cri-Kee uses his legs to write up a letter.  He</stage>
<stage>finishes and Mushu takes the paper]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Okay, okay, let me see what you've got.  From General Li, dear son, we're waiting for the huns at the pass and it would mean a lot</sp>
<stage>if you'd come and back us up.  [sarcastically]  That's great except you forgot, "and since we're all out of potpourri, maybe you wouldn't</stage>
<stage>mind bringing up some."  Hellooooo, this is the army!  Make it sound more urgent, please!  You know what I'm talkin' about?  [Cri-Kee starts</stage>
<stage>writing the note again]  That's better, much better.  [taking the note] Okay, Let's go.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Khan drinking water from the trough.  Mushu is on his back]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Khan-ie baby, hey, we need a ride.  [Khan squirts Mushu off his back with water from his mouth]</sp>

<stage>[Cut to Chi Fu walking out of the lake wrapped in a towel, sounds of laughter can be heart from the troops]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [muttering]:  Insubordinate ruffians.  [then calling to the troops]  You men owe me a new pair of slippers.  And I do not squeal like a</stage>
<stage>girl.  [a panda bear chomps down on the slipper Chi Fu is holding] Aaaaaahhhhhh!</stage>

<stage>Mushu [sitting on top of the panda bear behind a dummy of a soldier using sticks to gesticulate with the dummy's arms to push the note</stage>
<stage>towards Chi Fu.  Cri-Kee works the mouth]:  Urgent news from the general!  [Chi Fu looks over the panda]  What's the matter, you've never</stage>
<stage>seen a 'black and white' before?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Who are you?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Excuse me!  I think the question is: who are you?  We're in a war man!  There's no time for stupid questions.  I should have your</sp>
<stage>hat for that, [the panda starts walking forward] snatch it right off of your head [swiping with an arm at Chi Fu's hat.  Mushu turns the upper</stage>
<stage>half of the dummy around after the panda passes Chi Fu.  Chi Fu begins reading the message].  But I'm feeling gracious today, so carry on</stage>
<stage>before I report you.  [the panda walks up a tree taking Mushu and Cri-Kee with him out of sight]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [looking around for Mushu but not finding him, then runs into Shang's tent]:  Captain.  Urgent news from the General.  We're needed</stage>
<stage>at the front.</stage>

<stage>Mushu [from up in the tree]:  Pack your bags Cri-Kee, we're movin' out.  [Cri-Kee high fives Mushu]</stage>

<stage>[Song:  A Girl Worth Fighting For]</stage>

<stage>Army Chorus [troops walking up hill]:</stage>
<stage>For a long time we've been </stage>
<stage>marching off to battle</stage>

<stage>Yao [close-up of Yao, then a shot of 2 cows]: </stage>
<stage>In a thundering herd </stage>
<stage>we feel a lot like cattle</stage>

<stage>Cow [spoken]:  Moo</stage>

<stage>Army Chorus [showing troops marching]:</stage>
<stage>Like the pounding beat </stage>
<stage>our aching feet aren't </stage>
<stage>easy to ignore</stage>

<stage>Ling [catching up to Yao and Chien-Po]:</stage>
<stage>Hey, think of instead,</stage>
<stage>A girl worth fighting for [Yao, Ling and Chien-Po look upwards dreamily]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [spoken from behind]: Huh?</stage>

<stage>Ling [grabbing Mulan and drawing her close while pulling out a centerfold]:</stage>
<stage>That's what I said, a girl </stage>
<stage>worth fighting for [Mulan runs away seeing the centerfold]</stage>

<stage>[artistry section where the images are drawn like painted people.  Ling is seen looking at a woman and then kissing her]</stage>
<stage>I want her paler than the </stage>
<stage>moon with eyes that </stage>
<stage>shine like stars</stage>

<stage>Yao [lifting and lowering a woman over his head then opening his chest to show a gaping wound that we can see the woman through]:</stage>
<stage>My girl will marvel at </stage>
<stage>my strength, adore my </stage>
<stage>battle scars</stage>

<stage>Chien-Po [Chien-Po and a woman circle around then land on the edge of a large bowl of rice as a cow, pig and chicken fall beside them]:</stage>
<stage>I couldn't care less what she'll </stage>
<stage>wear or what she looks like</stage>
<stage>It all depends on what </stage>
<sp><speaker>she cooks like</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Beef, pork, chicken... [end painted people section, the last image fades into statues that the troops just passed]</stage>

<sp><speaker>All Three</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Mmm...</stage>

<stage>Yao [looking at Mulan while crossing the river with swords over their heads.  Mulan looks disgusted and hurries forward]:</stage>
<stage>Bet the local girls thought </stage>
<stage>you were quite the charmer</stage>

<stage>Ling [with armor full of water to make him look muscular]:</stage>
<stage>And I'll bet the ladies love </stage>
<stage>a man in armor [the water leaks out making Ling look like his normal self]</stage>

<stage>Army Chorus [Mushu whistles to ladies working in the rice field from out of the carriage holding cannons.  Cri-Kee looks shocked.  The</stage>
<stage>ladies look and giggle at Mulan who hides her face]:</stage>
<stage>You can guess what we </stage>
<stage>have missed the most </stage>
<stage>since we went off </stage>
<stage>to war</stage>
<stage>What do we want?</stage>
<stage>A girl worth fighting for!</stage>

<stage>Yao [Mulan walks away from Yao and into Chien-Po]:</stage>
<stage>My girl will think I have </stage>
<stage>no faults</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chien-Po</speaker> </sp>
<stage>That I'm a major find</stage>

<stage>Mulan [Caught between Yao, Ling, and Chien-Po who all look up dreamily waiting for her ideal woman.  She is forced to speak (sing)]:</stage>
<stage>[spoken] Uh, [singing] How about a girl who's </stage>
<stage>got a brain,  [Yao starts to look unimpressed]</stage>
<stage>Who always speaks her mind? [Mulan shrugs her shoulders]</stage>

<stage>Ling, Yao and Chien-Po [disdainfully, looking disappointed and disgusted]: Nah!</stage>

<stage>Ling [grabbing Mulan's shoulder and leaning on her, she takes his hand off and shakes her head disapprovingly.  Ling leans against the</stage>
<stage>carriage of cannons]:</stage>
<stage>My manly ways and turns of </stage>
<stage>phrase are sure to thrill her</stage>

<stage>Yao [hitting Khan so that the carriage runs out from under Ling.  Ling looks upset then falls in the mud]:</stage>
<stage>He thinks he's such a </stage>
<stage>lady-killer!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> </sp>
<stage>I've a girl back home who's </stage>
<stage>unlike any other.</stage>

<stage>Yao [aside to Mulan]:</stage>
<stage>Yeah, the only girl who'd </stage>
<stage>love him is his mother! [Mulan smiles]</stage>

<stage>Army Men [lining up locking arms across each others shoulders with Mulan in the middle to her discontent]:</stage>
<stage>But when we come home </stage>
<stage>in victory they'll line up </stage>
<stage>at the door!</stage>

<stage>Ling [sitting on top of Chien-Po]:</stage>
<stage>What do we want?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Army Chorus</speaker> </sp>
<stage>A girl worth fighting for!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Ling</speaker> </sp>
<stage>Wish that I had</stage>

<stage>Army Chorus [Mulan breaks away and walks in the opposite direction of the army]:</stage>
<stage>A girl worth fighting for!</stage>
<stage>(whistle) [Mulan sees Ling, Yao, and Chien-Po with snowballs about to pelt her so she turns around] </stage>
<stage>A girl worth fighting--</stage>

<stage>[All have stunned looks on their faces]</stage>

<stage>[End Song]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to ruins of a burned out village.  The soldiers walk through the singed gate and look around at the few planks that remain from the</stage>
<stage>buildings]</stage>

<stage>Shang [from mounted horse]:  Search for survivors.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan walking around the burned-out village.  She finds a the doll that Shan-Yu was holding and looks up sorrowfully.  Shang</stage>
<stage>comes to her side]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> I don't understand.  My father should have been here.</sp>

<stage>Chi Fu [calling out from the top of a hill overlooking a valley]:  Captain!  </stage>

<stage>[Chi Fu points down to the valley where the remains of General Li's army can be seen.  Flags poking up out of the snow, armor lying face</stage>
<stage>down, broken cannon carts.  Ling, Yao, Mulan, and a soldier have the look of horror on their faces as they look into the valley.  Chien-Po</stage>
<stage>walks up from the valley carrying a helmet]</stage>

<stage>Chien-po [handing the helmet to Shang]:  ...the General.</stage>

<stage>[Shang takes the helmet and walks to the edge of the hill.  He draws his sword and stabs it into the snow upright.  He kneels down and</stage>
<stage>places the helmet on top of the sword.  Mulan approaches him from behind]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [softly]:  I'm sorry.</stage>

<stage>[Shang gets up, turns around and puts his hand on Mulan's shoulder and he walks by.  Shang walks to the center of the troops. He grabs his</stage>
<stage>horse by the saddle, takes one quick look of grief then mounts his horse]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> The Huns are moving quickly.  We'll make better time to the Imperial City through the Tung Shao Pass.  We're the only hope for the</sp>
<stage>Emperor now.  Move out!</stage>

<stage>[Mulan looks at the sword, takes out the doll she found and places the doll at the base of the sword.  She turns around and joins the rest of</stage>
<stage>the troops marching on]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan standing next to Khan saddled to the cart with cannons.  A cannon blast shoots out of the cart and explodes in the air.  The</stage>
<stage>troops look surprised.  Mulan glances back with a scowl into the hole in the canopy of the cart to see Mushu with a sorrowful face.  Mushu</stage>
<stage>points at Cri-Kee.  Shang charges up to Mulan on his horse, Chi Fu right behind]</stage>

<stage>Shang [angrily]:  What happened?!</stage>

<stage>Mulan [stumbling]:  Uhhh--</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> You just gave away our position.  Now we're--[an arrow hits Shang in the shoulder as he falls to the ground.  Shang pulls out the</sp>
<stage>arrow]  [calling out] Get out of range!!</stage>

<stage>[The troops hurriedly run away as many arrows start falling all around them.  Mulan pulls Khan by the reins to hurry him up.  Fire arrows</stage>
<stage>start hitting the cart with cannons attached to Khan.  The cart begins to blaze with fire]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Save the cannons!</sp>

<stage>[The troops form a human chain and start taking the cannons out of the burning cart one by one while Mulan steadies Khan to keep him</stage>
<stage>from bolting.  Chien-Po grabs many and hauls them on his own.  The troops grab]as many cannons as they safely can and Mulan cuts Khan</stage>
<stage>free from the cart.  She mounts Khan and charges away from the fire.  The cart explodes sending Mulan flying off Khan losing her helmet</stage>
<stage>and sword which land near her.  Mushu and Cri-Kee, sent flying by the blast, scream and land near Mulan.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Oh sure, save the horse.</sp>

<stage>[Mulan grabs Mushu with her right hand and grabs the sword with her left and runs to the troops position.  Cri-Kee and Khan follow.  Yao,</stage>
<stage>Ling, Chien-Po and other recruits set up cannons against rocks.  They dodge a set of arrows that fall around them]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Fire!</sp>

<stage>[They launch a volley at the mountain where the archers are stationed.  As the cannon fire explodes, Shan-Yu's army hides]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Fire!</sp>

<stage>[Mulan, Ling and Chien-Po launch a second volley at the mountain where the archers are stationed.  No more arrows can be seen coming</stage>
<stage>from the mountain position]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Hold the last cannon.  [Yao poised to light his cannon, pauses.  Shan-Yu and his troops appear at the top of the mountain]  Prepare</sp>
<stage>to fight.  If we die, we die with honor.</stage>

<stage>[Shan-Yu raises his sword high above his head and charges down the mountain at Shang's position.  His falcon flies off his shoulder on</stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu's war cry  The Hun army follows]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Yao, aim the cannon at Shan-Yu.</sp>

<stage>[The line of Shang's troops with Mulan at the end draw their swords.  Mulan looks down at her sword and sees the reflection of a large snow</stage>
<stage>embankment hanging to the side of a cliff.  She rushes forward]</stage>

<stage>Yao [being pushed aside by Mulan as she grabs the cannon]:  Hey.</stage>
<stage> </stage>
<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Ping, come back.  Ping!</sp>

<stage>[Mulan charges forward towards the oncoming horde of the Hun army being led by Shan-Yu and his falcon.  Mushu looks over her at the</stage>
<stage>oncoming horde with worry in his eyes]</stage>

<stage>Shang [starting to run after her waving his arms]:  Stop!</stage>

<stage>[Mulan plants the cannon and aims it for the cliff with the snow overhang]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [seeing Shan-Yu riding closer to their position]:  All right, you might want to light that right about now.  Quickly!  Quickly!</stage>

<stage>[Mulan takes out the flint and tries to light the fuse.  Shan-Yu's falcon swoops buy knocking Mulan down scattering the flint rock]</stage>

<stage>Yao [speaking to Ling and Chien-Po]:  C'mon, we've gotta help.  [they charge towards Mulan's position]</stage>

<stage>[Mulan searches for the flint in the snow in vain.  She sees Mushu, grabs him and stretches him causing him to light the fuse.  Mushu lands</stage>
<stage>on the cannon and the cannon fires off just above the charging Shan-Yu]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [tailing off as he rides the cannon toward the snow embankment]:  You missed him!  How could you miss?  He was three feet in</stage>
<stage>front of you!</stage>

<stage>[The cannon lodges in the snow and explodes causing the beginning of a large avalanche.  Mulan looks up with an evil grin on her face and</stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu watches in horror as many of his troops begin to be swallowed up by the snow]</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [recollecting himself and focusing in on Mulan]:  Yrrrrrrraah.  </stage>

<stage>[Shan-Yu swipes at Mulan with his sword hitting her in the right side.  Mulan falls back grabbing her right side.  Shan-Yu's horse stumbles. </stage>
<stage>Mulan uses this break to bolt away from the avalanche.  Shan-Yu gains his composure and starts to gallop away from the avalanche on his</stage>
<stage>horse.  Shang looks with shock as hee sees the avalanche coming toward him.   Mulan grabs Shang as she passes by him, turning him</stage>
<stage>around and helping him run away from the avalanche]</stage>

<stage>Yao, Chien-Po and Ling [running towards the oncoming avalanche]:  Yeeahhhhhh!  [they stop.  noticing the oncoming avalanche they  turn</stage>
<stage>around and run back to where they came from]  Waaaaaaaaaa!</stage>

<stage>[Khan jumps away from the troops position and starts to run towards Mulan passing Ling, Yao and Chien-Po. The avalanche swallows up</stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu and his horse.  Khan arrives at Mulan's position just ahead of the avalanche.  Mulan jumps onto Khan and reaches for Shang.  She</stage>
<stage>grabs his hand, then the avalanche rushes forth breaking their grip, turning Khan around facing the oncoming avalanche of snow]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Ling, Yao and Chien-Po standing behind a rock.  They see the snow approaching close and run to larger shelter where the rest of</stage>
<stage>Shang's army is positioned just as the avalance reaches their posision]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mushu riding down the snow on a shield]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [calling out]:  Mulan!  Mulan!  [seeing hair sticking up from the snow] Mulan?  [Mushu picks up the Hun by the hair]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Hun Soldier</speaker> Arrrrr.</sp>

<stage>Mushu [pushing the hun soldier back under the snow]:  Nope.  Mulan!  [Mushu picks up Cri-Kee out of the snow]  Man, you are one lucky</stage>
<stage>bug.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan riding Khan above the snow into the teeth of the avalanche.  Khan and Mulan are swept under by the snow and reemerge</stage>
<stage>quickly.  She looks back and sees Shang passed out riding the wave of snow]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [calling loudly]:  Shang, Shang!  [Mulan turns around and rides to Shang's position.  She picks him up and places him on Khan.  She</stage>
<stage>turns Khan around again to be riding upstream]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Chien-Po with Ling standing on him and Yao standing on top of Ling]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chien-Po</speaker> Do you see them?</sp>

<stage>Yao [extatically]:  Yes! [Yao shoots an arrow with a rope attached]  Perfect!  Now I'll pull them to safe--[Yao grasps at air as the rope</stage>
<stage>completely passed through his hands]--ty.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan and Shang on Khan with Mushu and Cri-Kee riding up to her on his shield]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [riding on the shield up to Mulan, Khan and Shang speaking loudly, above the noise of the avalanche]:  Hey Mulan, I found a lucky</stage>
<stage>cricket.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [speaking loudly]:  We need help!  [Yao's arrow lands near by Mulan and she picks it up and starts to tie the rope to Khan]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [Getting off the shield and carrying Cri-Kee with him]:  Ooo, nice, very nice, you can sit by me.  [Mushu sees that they're about to fall</stage>
<stage>over the cliff.  He and Cri-Kee look frightened] Ahhhhh!  We're gonna die!  We're gonna die!  I know we're gonna die!  No way we can</stage>
<stage>survive this!  Death is coming! [Mulan knocks the arrow and shoots it toward Yao]</stage>

<stage>Yao [crying]:  I let them slip through my fingers. [Mulan's arrow lands in Yao's hands.  He grabs on and is pulled toward the cliff, the soldiers</stage>
<stage>grab onto Yao and hold him steady near the cliff edge with the rope taught over the cliff]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Pull</sp>

<stage>[Chien-Po prays as he calmly walks up to the group of soldiers.  He lifts them all up and pulls backward hauling Mulan, Shang, Khan, Mushu</stage>
<stage>and Cri-Kee to safety]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> I knew we could to it.  You da man. [Mulan looks pleased] Well sorta. [Mulan grimaces]</sp>

<stage>[The soldiers help them up to the cliff]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Ling</speaker> Step back guys, give 'em some air.</sp>

<stage>Shang [catching his breath]:  Ping, you are the craziest man I've ever met.  And for that I owe you my life.  From now on, you have my trust.</stage>
<stage>[Mulan smiles big]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Ling</speaker> Let's hear it for Ping!  The bravest of us all.</sp>

<stage>Yao [lifting his arm high]:  You're king of the mountain!</stage>

<stage>Chien-Po [jumping up and down]:  Yes, yes, yes!</stage>

<stage>Mulan [beginning to stand up]:  Ahhh, [she clutches her right side]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Ping, what's wrong?  [Mulan removes her hand slightly to show the blood on her hand and seeping through the armour] [loudly] </sp>
<stage>He's wounded, get help!  [Ping starts to pass out.  The images of Shang, Yao, Ling, and Chien-Po begin to fade as she loses consciousness] </stage>
<stage>Ping, hold on.  Hold on.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to outside of the medic tent.  Mulan and Medic are inside.  Shang stands by the entrance.  Yao, Ling and Chien-Po look quite</stage>
<stage>concerned.  Ling drums his fingers on his knees.  The medic comes out from the tent and whispers to Shang.  Shang looks astonished and</stage>
<stage>goes into the tent.  Mulan is lying down.  She opens her eyes, sees Shang and smiles at the sight of him.  She sits up allowing the blanket to</stage>
<stage>fall to her waist revealing her form fitting bandages on her chest.  She sees Shang's surprised look and realizes her feminine form is</stage>
<stage>noticeable]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [gasping as she covers up]: Huh,  I can explain.</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [stepping into the tent]:  Huh?  So it's true.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [calling after Shang as he steps out of the tent]:  Shang!</stage>

<stage>[Cut to outside the tent.  Chi Fu hauls out Mulan by the arm.  Mulan uses her other hand to hold the blanket]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> I knew there was something wrong with you.  [Chi Fu takes off Mulan's hair tie and throws her to the ground]  A woman.</sp>

<stage>[Ling, Yao and Chien-Po are shocked]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [to the troops]:  Trecherous snake.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [on the ground kneeling and hunched over, speaking to Shang]:  My name is Mulan.  I did it to save my father.</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [to the troops]:  High treason!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> I didn't mean for it to go this far.</sp>

<stage>Chi Fu [getting in Mulan's face and speaking to her while she whinces]:  Ultimate dishonor.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> It was the only way.  Please believe me.</sp>

<stage>Chi Fu [to Shang]:  Hmph, Captain?</stage>

<stage>[Shang walks over to Khan and takes the sword out of the scabbard attached to Khan.  Khan rears back]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [to the soldier by Khan]:  Restrain him.</stage>

<stage>[Shang walks toward Mulan with sword in hand]</stage>

<stage>Yao, Ling and Chien-Po [rushing toward Mulan]:  Noooooo!</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [putting his hand to stop Ling, Yao, and Chien-Po from proceeding further]:  You know the law.</stage>

<stage>[Shang stands over Mulan.  Mulan looks at Shang then bows her head in anticipation.  Shang lifts the sword high above his head and throws</stage>
<stage>it down in front of Mulan]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> A life for a life.  My debt is repaid.  [turns and walks towards the Imperial City]  Move out!</sp>

<stage>Chi Fu [coming up to Shang's face]:  But you can't just...</stage>

<stage>Shang [getting in Chi Fu's face]:  I said, "Move out!"</stage>

<stage>[The troops walk off toward the Imperial City leaving Mulan behind with Khan, Cri-Kee, and Mushu.  Mulan is sitting, shivering. Khan takes</stage>
<stage>his blanket and wraps it around Mulan with his mouth and sits behind her.  Cri-Kee lights a fire with twigs.  When he doesn't get warm, he</stage>
<stage>moves under the blanket wrapped around Mulan.  Mushu walks toward Mulan carrying a stick]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> I was this close, this close to impressing the ancestors, getting the top shelf, an entourage.  Man, all my fine work, ffft.  [Mushu picks</sp>
<stage>up a dumpling with his stick, slumps down in front of the fire Cri-Kee made and begins to cook the dumpling over the fire] [glancing up] Hi.</stage>

<stage>Mulan [look of sadness]:  I should never have left home.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Eh, come on, you wanted to save your father's life.  Who knew you'd end up shaming him, disgracing your ancestors, and losing all</sp>
<stage>your friends.  You know, you just gotta, you gotta learn to let these things go [looking as if he's about to cry].</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Maybe I didn't go for my father.  Maybe what I really wanted was to prove I could do things right.  So when I looked in the mirror</sp>
<stage>[picking up her helmet and looking at her reflection in her helmet] I'd see someone worthwhile.  But I was wrong.  I see nothing.  [throws the</stage>
<stage>helmet down and a tear runs down her cheek]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [picking up the helmet and spitting on it]:  Well that's because this just needs a little spit, that's all.  Let me shine this up for ya [wiping</stage>
<stage>the spit to clean the helmet and holding it up to Mulan].   I can see you, look at you, you look so pretty.  [seeing Mulan is not cheered up by</stage>
<stage>his actions, he shows sorrow on his face]  The truth is we're both frauds.  Your ancestors never sent me, they don't even like me.  I mean,</stage>
<stage>you risked your life to help people you love.  I risked your life to help myself.  At least you had good intentions  [Mulan smiles].</stage>

<stage>Cri-Kee [jumping on top of the helmet beginning to bawl]:  Chirp, Chirp, Chirp.  Bawl, Bawl.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> What!?  What do you mean you're not lucky?  You lied to me?  [Cri-Kee nods] [to Khan]  And what are you? A sheep?</sp>

<stage>Mulan [sadly]:  I'll have to face my father sooner or later.  Let's go home.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Yeah, this ain't gonna be pretty.  But, don't you worry, 'kay?  Things'll work out.  We started this thing together and that's how we'll</sp>
<stage>finish. [Mushu hugs Mulan.  Mulan smiles]  I promise.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Shan-Yu's falcon flying over the avalanche site.  Shan-Yu's hand pops out of the snow.  He gets up and glances around]</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [screaming]:  Rrrrrrraaaaaaaaahhh!</stage>

<stage>[Hun Archer, Long-Hair Hun Man, Hun Strong Guy, Hun Bald Man #1, and Hun Bald Man #2 each pop out of the snow and join</stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu.  They set off towards the Imperial City]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [seeing them from behind, gasps]:  Huh.  [Mulan runs, grabs her sword, mounts Khan, and heads out following the Huns to the</stage>
<stage>Imperial City]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Home is that way! [points to the opposite direction Mulan is heading]</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> I have to do something.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Did you see those Huns!?  They popped out of the snow, like daisies!</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Are we in this together or not?</sp>

<stage>Cri-Kee [emphatically]:  Chirp, Chirp.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Well, let's go kick some Huny buns!  [Jumps onto Khan and utters fighting words as they ride off to the Imperial City]  Wu Hu Ha</sp>
<stage>Ga, Wu Hu Ha Ga</stage>

<stage>[Cut to the victory parade in the Imperial City.  Fireworks go off, kites are flying.  The drummers march by, followed by the flutist, followed</stage>
<stage>by the acrobats.  The Parade Leader follows, then Shang and his men, followed by lion dancers]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Parade Leader</speaker> Make way for the heros of China.</sp>

<stage>[Shang leads the men on horseback, all have sorrowful looks on their faces.  Mulan rides up through the crowd and stops.  She looks around</stage>
<stage>and sees Shang in the parade]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [calling out]:  Shang! [riding next to him]</stage>

<stage>Shang [surprised]:  Mulan?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> The Huns are alive, they're in the city.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> You don't belong here Mulan, go home.</sp>

<stage>Mulan [with a scowl rides khan to the other side of Shang]:  Shang, I saw them in the mountains.  You have to believe me.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Why should I?</sp>

<stage>Mulan [riding ahead to block Shang's horse]:  Why else would I come back?  You said you'd trust Ping.  Why is Mulan any different?</stage>

<stage>[Shang turns his horse and rides around Mulan and goes forward]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [to Yao, Chien-Po and Ling]:  Keep your eyes open.  I know they're here.  Hya.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan rides off and stops near the entrance to the palace, she dismounts Khan and runs into the palace yard]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Now where are you going?</sp>

<stage>Mulan [calling over her shoulder]:  To find someone who will believe me.  [Mulan runs into the palace yard]  </stage>

<stage>[Cut to the parade procession stopping in front of the Emperor on the steps of the palace.  Chi Fu stands next to Shang and gives him</stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu's sword.  The Lion dancers stop behind Shang.  A palace man strikes a large gong and the people fall silent]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> My children, heaven smiles down upon the Middle Kingdom.  China will sleep safely tonight thanks to our brave warriors.</sp>

<stage>[The crowd cheers]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan at the fringe of the crowd]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [approaching Man #1 laying her hand on his shoulder]:  Sir, the Emperor's in danger! [Man #1 rips his shoulder away from Mulan's</stage>
<stage>touch and moves away] [agitated]  But the Huns are here!  [Mulan walks up to Man #2]  Please, you have to help me.  [Man #2 walks</stage>
<stage>away from Mulan] [turning to Mushu who is standing near her in the yard]  No one will listen!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Huh?  Oh, I'm sorry, did you say something?</sp>

<stage>Mulan [irritatedly]:  Mushu!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Hey, you're a girl again, remember?</sp>

<stage>[Cut to Shang holding the sword before the Emperor]</stage>

<stage>Shang [kneeling down giving the sword to the Emperor]:  Your Majesty, I present to you the sword of Shan-Yu.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> I know what this means to you, Captain Li.  Your father would have been very proud.</sp>

<stage>[Shan-Yu's falcon swoops down and takes the sword as Shang is giving it to the Emperor.  The falcon rises above the roof and drops the</stage>
<stage>sword to Shan-Yu who was sitting next to the gargoyles in the shadows blending in.  He rises out of the shadows to catch the sword so that</stage>
<stage>all the people can see his face.  The masses of people gasp at the sight of Shan-Yu.  Shang begins to draw his sword.  All 5 of Shan-Yu's</stage>
<stage>men jump out from behind the dragon knocking down Shang and grab the Emperor knocking off his hat.  Hun Bald Man #1 and #2 carry</stage>
<stage>the Emperor into the Palace.  Long-Haired Hun Man and Hun Strong Guy close the palace doors as Hun archer knocks his arrow retreating</stage>
<stage>into the Palace to threaten would be rescue attempts]</stage>

<stage>Shang [getting up and running toward the closing doors]:  No.</stage>

<stage>Yao [beckoning to the other soldiers]:  C'mon.</stage>

<stage>[Shang reaches the palace doors just as they close with all the Huns inside]</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [laughs evily]:  Ha, Ha, Ha, Ha, Ha, Ha.</stage>

<stage>[Shang and his soldiers pick up a big stone statue and use it as a battering ram.  They are unsuccessful at opening the door.  Mulan sees</stage>
<stage>what's going on and arrives at the steps]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [to herself]:  They'll never reach the Emperor in time.  [She looks at the columns and runs near to the Shang and his soldiers.  She</stage>
<stage>whistles loudly catching the soldiers' attention]  Hey guys, I've got an idea.  [Mulan runs around the palace to the right towards the columns]</stage>

<stage>[Song:  I'll Make a Man Out of You (reprise) plays in the background during the next action sequence]</stage>

<stage>(Be a man) </stage>
<stage>We must be swift as </stage>
<stage>the coursing river</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the force </stage>
<stage>of a great typhoon</stage>
<stage>(Be a man)</stage>
<stage>With all the strength </stage>
<stage>of a raging fire</stage>
<stage>Mysterious as the </stage>
<stage>dark side of the moon</stage>

<stage>[Yao, Ping and Chien-Po look at one another then drop the statue and follow Mulan.  Shang looks astonished.  Around the corner Yao, Ling</stage>
<stage>and Chien-Po begin to take off their armor and dress as women.  Once the transformation is complete, they take out their sashes and</stage>
<stage>prepare to shimmy up the columns.  Shang arrives and taps Mulan on the shoulder.  He takes off his cape and wraps it around the column</stage>
<stage>to signify that he's coming along.  They shimmy up the poles together]</stage>

<stage>[End song]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Hun Bald Man #1 and #2 arriving with the Emperor and a high balcony within the palace.  Shan-Yu drops down from the roof]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shan-Yu</speaker> Boo.  [Shan-Yu steps into the balcony next to the Emperor] [to Hun Bald Man #1 and #2] Guard the door [they walk off down</sp>
<stage>the stairs that lead to the balcony].  [pacing around the Emperor]  Your walls and armies have fallen, and now it's your turn.  Bow to me.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to the entrance to the stairwell that leads to the balcony.  Hun Bald Man #1 and #2 come down the stairs and close the door, joining</stage>
<stage>Hun Archer Man, Hun Strong Man and Hun Long-Hair Man.  Mulan and company are around the corner]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [whispering]:  Okay, any questions?</stage>

<stage>Yao [whispering]:  Does this dress make me look fat? [Mulan slaps him]  Ow.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan, Yao, Ling and Chien-Po walk out smiling, giggling and trying to act lady-like including holding fans and waving fans]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Hun Archer</speaker> Who's there?</sp>

<stage>Hun Bald Man #2 [putting down Hun Bald Man #1's sword]:  Concubines.</stage>

<stage>Hun Bald Man #1:  Ugly concubines.</stage>

<stage>Ling [waving daintily, speaking to Yao]:  Oh he's so cute.</stage>

<stage>[Hun Bald Man #2 smiles and waves back.  Hun Bald Man #1 elbows Hun Bald Man #2.  A bitten apple falls out from beneath Ling's</stage>
<stage>dress.  He pulls the dress out and turns so as not to expose the loss of figure]</stage>

<stage>Shang [from around the corner putting his head down into his hand]:  Aww.</stage>

<stage>[Shan-Yu's Falcon sees Shang and starts to squawk.  Mushu from above singes off all his feathers with his fire breathing]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [to Cri-Kee sitting above him]:  Now that's what I call Mongolian Barbeque.  [Cri-Kee rolls on his back in laughter.  The stunned</stage>
<stage>falcon doesn't do anything]</stage>

<stage>[Hun Bald Man #2 picks up the apple and offers it back to Ling.  Ling, Yao, and Chien-Po pull out the fruit they were using to simulate a</stage>
<stage>woman's chest.  Chien-Po takes his watermelons and smashes them on the heads of Hun Bald Man #1 and #2.  He then smashes their two</stage>
<stage>heads together and they fall to the ground.  Ling pushes the apple into Hun Long-Hair man's mouth and kicks him in the stomach causing</stage>
<stage>Hun Long-Hair Man to stoop over on the ground.  Ling uses his head to crack Hun Long-Hair Man's back.  Hun Strong Guy lunges his fist</stage>
<stage>at Yao and misses, he misses with the other.  Yao grabs the outstretched arm and flips him over onto his head. Mulan kicks away Hun</stage>
<stage>Archer Man's bow and knocked arrow, avoids his strike by turning her back to Hun Archer.  She follows with a left elbow to the stomach</stage>
<stage>followed by a left upper cut knocking Hun Archer to the ground.  She sits on his back and uses the bow to pull his head back]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [calling out]:  Shang, GO!</stage>

<stage>[Shang runs out from behind the corner, charges through the door and runs up the stairs]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Shan-Yu and the Emperor on the balcony]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shan-Yu</speaker> I tire of your arrogance old man.  [yelling and putting his sword at the emperor's</sp>
<stage>throat] Bow to me!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> No matter how the wind howls, the mountain cannot bow to it.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Shan-Yu</speaker> Then you will kneel in pieces. [Shan-Yu draws back his sword to strike the Emperor]</sp>

<stage>[Shang runs up in time to block the striking blow of Shan-Yu with his sword.  Shang swipes with</stage>
<stage>his sword.  Shan-Yu grabs Shang's arm and throws him towards the edge.  Shang grabs onto a column</stage>
<stage>and he flies over the edge and uses the momentum to swing back and kick Shan-Yu.  Shan-Yu falls</stage>
<stage>to the ground, Shang on top of him. Shang punches Shan-Yu.  Shan-Yu grabs Shang and rolls over</stage>
<stage>forcing Shang to be on his back underneath him.  Shang uses his knee to hit Shan-Yu from behind</stage>
<stage>as he uses his hand to hit him in the head.  Shang forces Shan-Yu onto his back and grabs his arm</stage>
<stage>pulling it behind Shan-Yu's back.  Mulan, Chien-Po, Yao and Ling enter the balcony from the</stage>
<stage>stairs]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Chien-Po, get the Emperor.</sp>

<stage>Chien-Po [standing in front of the Emperor and bowing]:  Sorry, your Majesty.  </stage>

<stage>[Chien-Po lifts up the Emperor and runs over to Mulan who is by a rope attached to a column in</stage>
<stage>the balcony.  Chien-Po uses his sash as a pulley and rides down the rope to the ground.  Shan Yu</stage>
<stage>watches the Emperor leave]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shan-Yu</speaker> No! </sp>

<stage> [Shan-Yu uses his free arm to elbow Shang in the face.  Shan-Yu gets up and head-butts Shang and</stage>
<stage>throws him to the ground.  Shang lies limp.  Mulan watches Shang fall then she looks over the</stage>
<stage>edge at Ling and Yao now on the ground.  Chien-Po runs off the screen out of sight]</stage>

<stage>Yao [motioning her to follow]:  Come on!</stage>

<stage>[Mulan looks down at Shang with a worried look.  Shan-Yu begins to approach Mulan and the rope. </stage>
<stage>Mulan looks at the approaching Shan-Yu and then down to spy his sword. Thinking quickly, Mulan grabs</stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu's sword and cuts the taught rope.  Shan-Yu reaches the edge and grabs for the falling rope unsuccessfully as Mulan leaves the</stage>
<stage>sword embedded in the column and runs to Shang's position.  The crowd cheers]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shan-Yu</speaker> No!  [He looks down at the crowd and realizes he cannot find the Emperor among the</sp>
<stage>throng of people]  Yrraaaaahhhh!</stage>

<stage>[Shan-Yu turns and looks back and sees Mulan looking concerned, holding up Shang.  Shan-Yu pulls</stage>
<stage>out his sword lodged in the column and heads toward them.  As Shang sees Shan-Yu approaching, he</stage>
<stage>puts his arm in front of Mulan to ask her to leave and takes out his knife.  Mulan slides away. </stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu comes up to Shang, knocks away his knife, slaps him in the face, and grabs Shang by the</stage>
<stage>shirt collar]</stage>

<stage>Shan-Yu [in Shang's face]:  You, you took away my victory.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan's shoe hits Shan-Yu in the head and bounces back to her feet.  Shan-Yu turns toward Mulan]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> No!  I did!  [Mulan pulls her hair back to look like she did when she was a soldier]</sp>

<stage>Shan-Yu [looking at Mulan]:  The soldier from the mountains.</stage>

<stage>[Shan-Yu drops Shang and starts after Mulan as she puts on her shoe and runs down the stairs and</stage>
<stage>through the doors to the balcony.  She closes the door with the latch falling in place right</stage>
<stage>behind her.  She leans against the doors.  Shan-Yu punches a hole in one door with his fist. </stage>
<stage>Mulan runs away from the doors down the corridor.  Mushu riding Shan-Yu's falcon like a horse</stage>
<stage>catches up with Mulan]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> So what's the plan?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Ummmm.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> You don't have a plan?!</sp>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Hey, I'm making this up as I...[looks out a window and spies the firework tower] go. </sp>
<stage>Mushu--</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> I'm way ahead of you sister.  C'mon Cri-Kee. [Mushu and Cri-Kee jump onto a kite and use</sp>
<stage>the wings to soar over toward the fireworks tower]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Shan-Yu.  Shan-Yu breaks through the doors and catches up to Mulan swinging his sword</stage>
<stage>wildly knocking down a support column with every swipe.  Mulan runs and ducks his every blow. </stage>
<stage>Mulan climbs up a column to get out of Shan-Yu's reach.  Shan-Yu slices the base of the column</stage>
<stage>causing it to fall and break through the outer wall.  Mulan screams as the beam falls and comes</stage>
<stage>to a stop.  Mulan gets up on the beam and jumps up to catch onto the awning.  She looks off to</stage>
<stage>her right and spies Mushu arriving at the fireworks tower]</stage>

<stage>[Zoom in on the fireworks tower.  Mushu lands near Barry Cook and Tony Bancroft (the firework</stage>
<stage>lighters) on the edge of the tower] </stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Citizens, I need firepower.</sp>

<sp><speaker>Barry Cook</speaker> Who are you?</sp>

<stage>Mushu [Mushu (using the wings from the kite) and Cri-Kee with wings spread like batman]:  You're</stage>
<stage>worst nightmare.</stage>

<stage>[Barry Cook and Tony Bancroft jump off the tower and plunge toward the ground]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan. She pulls herself onto the roof and climbs up to the crest]</stage>

<stage>Man in Crowd #1:  On the roof.</stage>

<stage>Man in Crowd #2:  Look!</stage>

<stage>[Mulan lines up where she is standing with the fireworks tower across the way.  Shan-Yu breaks</stage>
<stage>through the roof behind Mulan surprising her.  Mulan backs away and searches for something on her</stage>
<stage>person to help her against Shan-Yu.  She finds a her fan, takes it out, and opens it]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shan-Yu</speaker> It looks like you're out of ideas.</sp>

<stage>[Shan-Yu lunges with his sword.  Mulan dodges to her right and lets the sword go right through</stage>
<stage>the fan.  She closes the fan back up on the sword and twists the fan with both hands so that</stage>
<stage>Shan-Yu loses his grip.  The sword flies toward Mulan and she catches it by the handle slipping</stage>
<stage>off the fan with her sword movement]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Not quite.  [calling out]  Ready, Mushu?</sp>

<stage>Mushu [behind Shan-Yu tied to a large rocket firework]:  I am ready, baby. [He blows fire onto a</stage>
<stage>stick and hands the stick to Cri-Kee who's standing on the firework]  Light me!  [Cri-Kee lights</stage>
<stage>the fuse]</stage>

<stage>[Shan-Yu approaches Mulan.  Using the sword as a lever, Mulan lunges at Shan-Yu kicking him in</stage>
<stage>the face then sweep kicks him and he falls to the ground.  Mulan picks the sword back up and</stage>
<stage>stabs it into Shan-Yu's cape.  The rocket on Mushu ignites and hurls him toward Shan-Yu.  Mulan</stage>
<stage>lies flat down on the left side of the roof.  Shan-Yu sees the approaching rocket and tries to</stage>
<stage>run, but the sword has him pinned to the spot.  The rocket hits Shan-Yu square in the belly</stage>
<stage>propelling him toward the firework tower.  Mushu grabbed onto the sword as he went by letting the</stage>
<stage>rocket do the work.  Cri-Kee hangs on to Mushu's tail.  Mulan jumps back up to the crest of the</stage>
<stage>roof and runs away from the fireworks tower grabbing Mushu and Cri-Kee off the sword]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [while running]:  Get off the roof, get off the roof, get off the roof.</stage>

<stage>[The rocket rides Shan-Yu into the fireworks tower causing masses of explosions and fireworks to</stage>
<stage>fly everywhere.  Mulan jumps near the edge of the roof.  Propelled by the explosion, she grabs</stage>
<stage>onto a lantern that is hanging on a taught rope and starts to slide down.  She looks down and</stage>
<stage>releases her grip so that she lands on the back of Shang causing the two of them to fall to the</stage>
<stage>ground.  Shan-Yu's sword follows and lands on the ground near by]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [landing and flying backwards on his butt a couple of times pointing at the fireworks]:  Ah</stage>
<stage>ha ha ha ha.  [Mushu's catches Cri-Kee with antenna on fire as Cri-Kee falls toward him] [to</stage>
<stage>Cri-Kee]  You are a lucky bug. [Mushu pinches out the fire on Cri-Kee's antenna]</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [walking down the stairs in a tattered outfit and slightly burned]:  That was a deliberate</stage>
<stage>attempt on my life.  Where is she?  Now she's done it.  What a mess.  [Shang and troops push</stage>
<stage>Mulan behind them to protect her] [to Shang] Stand aside, that creature's not worth protecting.</stage>

<stage>Shang [in Chi Fu's face]:  She's a hero.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> 'Tis a woman.  She will never be worth anything.</sp>

<stage>Shang [grabbing Chi Fu by the shirt collar]:  Listen, you pompous--</stage>

<stage>Emperor [walking down the steps]:  That is enough!</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Your Majesty, I can explain.</sp>

<stage>[The Emperor motions for Shang to stand aside.  Shang and his men part giving the Emperor a clear</stage>
<stage>path to Mulan.  Mulan steps forward and bows before the Emperor.  Chi Fu with a sinister look</stage>
<stage>waits to write down the words of the Emperor]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> I've heard a great deal about you, Fa Mulan.  You stole your father's armor, ran away</sp>
<stage>from home, impersonated a soldier, deceived your commanding officer, dishonored the Chinese army,</stage>
<stage>destroyed my palace, AND...you have saved us all.  [the Emperor bows to Mulan]</stage>

<stage>[Chi Fu looks at the Emperor actions astonishingly then immediately falls prostrate before Mulan. </stage>
<stage>Shang, Yao, Ling, and Chien-Po follow suit.  Mulan looks up then turns around hardly believing</stage>
<stage>what she sees as the entire Chinese population within the palace grounds fall prostrate on the</stage>
<stage>ground in a wave like pattern, bowing to her.  Khan bows with Mushu and Cri-Kee on his back]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> My little baby's all grown up and savin' China.  [to Cri-Kee] You have a tissue?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> Chi Fu,</sp>

<sp><speaker>Chi Fu</speaker> Your Excellency?</sp>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> See to it that this woman is made a member of my council.</sp>

<stage>Chi Fu [muttering to himself]:  A member of your coun...[realizing what the Emperor has said]</stage>
<stage>what? [stutters] But there are no council positions open, your Majesty.</stage>

<stage>Emperor [to Mulan]:  Very well then, you can have his job [pointing out Chi Fu].</stage>

<stage>Chi Fu [wobbling to and fro]:  What?...My...[faints]</stage>

<stage>Mulan [smiles big then turns to the Emperor and bows]:  With all due respect, your Excellency.  I</stage>
<stage>have been away from home long enough.</stage>

<stage>Emperor [taking off his pendant]:  Then take this, so your family will know what you have done</stage>
<stage>for me.  And this [handing her the sword of Shan-Yu]  so the world will know what you have done</stage>
<stage>for China.</stage>

<stage>[Mulan takes the gifts and hugs the Emperor]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Yao</speaker> Is she allowed to do that?  [Shang, Ling, and Chien-Po shrug]</sp>

<stage>[Mulan walks away from the Emperor and is embraced by Yao and Ling.  Chien-Po comes up and lifts</stage>
<stage>all three of them off the ground in a big bear hug.  Chien-Po lets them all back to the ground</stage>
<stage>again.  Mulan walks toward Shang and stops in front of him.  As Shang begins to speak Mulan</stage>
<stage>starts to smile anticipating something good]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> Um...[Mulan grins]  You... [Mulan smiles] You fight good.</sp>

<stage>Mulan [smile turning into disappointment]:  Oh, thank you.  [Mulan walks toward Khan]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Shang</speaker> [turning toward Mulan and grunts with disappointment in himself]:  Hmm.</sp>

<stage>[Mulan mounts Khan]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Khan, let's go home.</sp>

<stage>[Khan jumps down the steps and gallops on the flat parts of the stair case back down to ground</stage>
<stage>level.  The crowd cheers al the while.  The Emperor approaches Shang and clears his throat]</stage>

<stage>Emperor [to Shang]:  The flower that blooms in adversity is the most rare and beautiful of all.</stage>

<stage>Shang [dumbfounded]:  Sir?</stage>

<sp><speaker>Emperor</speaker> You don't meet a girl like that ev'ry dynasty.  [The emperor puts on his hat and walks</sp>
<stage>back up the steps to his palace]</stage>

<stage>[Cut to Mulan's home, her father is sitting beneath the blossom tree.   A blossom falls and lands</stage>
<stage>on his leg.  Mulan appears at the threshold and moves toward her father.  Fa Zhou sees her</stage>
<stage>approaching and starts to stand]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> Mulan.  </sp>

<stage>[Mulan quickly moves in front of her father and kneels causing him to sit back down]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Father, I brought you the sword of Shan-Yu [hands the sword to Fa Zhou] and the crest of</sp>
<stage>the Emperor [hands the crest to Fa Zhou].  [with head bowed] They're gifts to honor the Fa</stage>
<stage>Family.</stage>

<stage>[Fa Zhou takes the gifts and throws them down to the ground beside him to the surprise of Mulan. </stage>
<stage>He bends down and holds her arms outstretched]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Fa Zhou</speaker> The greatest gift and honor, is having you for a daughter.  [Fa Zhou wipes away Mulan's</sp>
<stage>tear then hugs Mulan]  I've missed you so.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> I've missed you too Baba.</sp>

<stage>[Fa li and Grandma Fa watch from the doorway]</stage>

<stage>Fa Li [sighing]:  Ahhhhh</stage>

<sp><speaker>Grandma Fa</speaker> Great, she brings home a sword.  If you ask me she should have brought home a</sp>
<stage>ma--[leaving her mouth open when she sees Shang]</stage>

<stage>Shang [just arriving]:  Excuse me, does Fa Mulan live here?</stage>

<stage>[Grandma Fa's mouth stays open as she and Fa Li point toward Mulan's position.  Shang walks</stage>
<stage>toward Mulan and Fa Zhou]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Grandma Fa</speaker> Woo, sign me up for the next war.</sp>

<stage>[Shang approaches seeing Fa Zhou]</stage>

<stage>Shang [bows before Fa Zhou and speaks confidently]:  Honorable Fa Zhou I--Mulan [Mulan steps up. </stage>
<stage>Shang sees her and speaks insecurely] Uh...Uh...You forgot your helmet.  Ah but well, actually</stage>
<stage>it's your helmet, isn't it?...[handing the helmet toward Fa Zhou] I mean...</stage>

<stage>[Fa Zhou motions with his head for Mulan to take over.  Mulan holds the helmet Shang offers]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Would you like to stay for dinner?</sp>

<stage>Grandma Fa [speaking from stage right]:  Would you like to stay forever? [Mulan shakes her head with a</stage>
<stage>smile at Grandma Fa's statement]</stage>

<stage>Shang [reassuredly to Mulan]:  Dinner would be great.</stage>

<stage>[Cut to First Ancestor grinning happily looking at the scene through the temple window.  He watches Mulan hand the helmet back to Fa</stage>
<stage>Zhou.  Mushu climbs up to the window sill by First Ancestor's his head]</stage>

<stage>Mushu [tugging on First Ancestor's ear]:  C'mon, who did a good job?  C'mon, tell me who did a</stage>
<stage>good job.</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [hesitantly]:  Oh, all right.  You can be a guardian again.</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Yeeeeeahhhhhhh.  [Mushu runs to his post and Cri-Kee bangs the gong awakening all the</sp>
<stage>ancestors]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mushu</speaker> Take it Cri-Kee.</sp>

<stage>[Song:  True to Your Heart -- No characters sing in the song]</stage>

<stage>[Ancestor 1 does a dance from Pulp Fiction while Ancestor 3 does the Hand Jive]</stage>

<stage>Ancestor 3 [spoken to Ancestor 1]:  She get's it from my side of the family.</stage>

<stage>Mushu [spoken while swinging on a chain]:  Call out for egg rolls!</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [disgusted]:  Guardians.</stage>

<stage>[Mushu lands on the steps outside the temple.  Mulan walks up to him and rests besides him on the</stage>
<stage>steps]</stage>

<sp><speaker>Mulan</speaker> Thanks, Mushu [kisses Mushu on the forehead].</sp>

<sp><speaker>Little Brother</speaker> Bark, bark, bark, bark, bark, bark, bark  </sp>

<stage>[Little brother runs up the steps and into the temple with the bag of grain tied to him.  The</stage>
<stage>chickens follow him in]</stage>

<stage>First Ancestor [annoyed]:  Mushu!</stage>

<stage>[Roll Credits]</stage>

<stage>[The End]</stage>
</root>